Zotero Export	11/6/2015	(Not Applicable)	Zotero/IEEE																																																																																			
Key	Item Type	Publication Year	Author	Title	Publication Title	ISBN	ISSN	DOI	Url	Abstract Note	Date	Date Added	Date Modified	Access Date	Pages	Num Pages	Issue	Volume	Number Of Volumes	Journal Abbreviation	Short Title	Series	Series Number	Series Text	Series Title	Publisher	Place	Language	Rights	Type	Archive	Archive Location	Library Catalog	Call Number	Extra	Notes	File Attachments	Link Attachments	Manual Tags	Automatic Tags	Editor	Series Editor	Translator	Contributor	Attorney Agent	Book Author	Cast Member	Commenter	Composer	Cosponsor	Counsel	Interviewer	Producer	Recipient	Reviewed Author	Scriptwriter	Words By	Guest	Number	Edition	Running Time	Scale	Medium	Artwork Size	Filing Date	Application Number	Assignee	Issuing Authority	Country	Meeting Name	Conference Name	Court	References	Reporter	Legal Status	Priority Numbers	Programming Language	Version	System	Code	Code Number	Section	Session	Committee	History	Legislative Body
X452JSBD	conferencePaper	2008	"Cole, Robert J.; Liu, Peng"	Addressing Low Base Rates in Intrusion Detection via Uncertainty-Bounding Multi-Step Analysis		978-0-7695-3447-3		10.1109/ACSAC.2008.14	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4721564		Dec-08	8/11/2015 13:09	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:09	269-278											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
MCMHWMP5	conferencePaper	2012	"Morais, Anderson; Cavalli, Ana"	A Distributed Intrusion Detection Scheme for Wireless Ad Hoc Networks	Proceedings of the 27th Annual ACM Symposium on Applied Computing	978-1-4503-0857-1		10.1145/2245276.2245382	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2245276.2245382	"Wireless ad hoc network is an emerging technology that is gaining popularity as a cost-effective way of offering end-to-end services, such as Internet access, in an inexpensive, practical, and fast manner. However, wireless ad hoc networks are particularly vulnerable to extern and insider attacks due to their very intrinsic nature such as shared wireless medium and decentralized architecture. In this paper, we present a distributed intrusion detection approach, which is based on exchange of events and cooperation between the participating nodes. The proposed mechanism relies on non-intrusive traffic monitoring at each node, which generates network events. These events are processed by the intrusion detection system that is able to instantly signalize malicious activities, for instance, a node disseminating fake routing information through the network. We demonstrate the approach efficiency for detecting misbehaving nodes through a virtualized network environment that consists of virtual nodes interconnected which represent the network topology."	2012	7/25/2014 19:55	7/25/2014 19:55	7/25/2014 19:55	556–562							SAC '12				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\XM57N4XK\Morais and Cavalli - 2012 - A Distributed Intrusion Detection Scheme for Wirel.pdf		network	intrusion detection; routing misbehavior; wireless ad hoc network																																														
R3EAHAFI	conferencePaper	2010	"Nehinbe, Joshua Ojo"	A Framework for Evaluating Clustering Algorithm		978-1-4244-9405-7		10.1109/CloudCom.2010.90	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=5708517		Nov-10	8/11/2015 13:08	9/2/2015 18:34	8/11/2015 13:08	677-686											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
457NJ3JB	journalArticle	2015	"Tang, Lu-An; Yu, Xiao; Gu, Quanquan; Han, Jiawei; Jiang, Guofei; Leung, Alice; Porta, Thomas La"	A Framework of Mining Trajectories from Untrustworthy Data in Cyber-Physical System	ACM Trans. Knowl. Discov. Data		1556-4681	10.1145/2700394	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2700394	"A cyber-physical system (CPS) integrates physical (i.e., sensor) devices with cyber (i.e., informational) components to form a context-sensitive system that responds intelligently to dynamic changes in real-world situations. The CPS has wide applications in scenarios such as environment monitoring, battlefield surveillance, and traffic control. One key research problem of CPS is called mining lines in the sand. With a large number of sensors (sand) deployed in a designated area, the CPS is required to discover all trajectories (lines) of passing intruders in real time. There are two crucial challenges that need to be addressed: (1) the collected sensor data are not trustworthy, and (2) the intruders do not send out any identification information. The system needs to distinguish multiple intruders and track their movements. This study proposes a method called LiSM (Line-in-the-Sand Miner) to discover trajectories from untrustworthy sensor data. LiSM constructs a watching network from sensor data and computes the locations of intruder appearances based on the link information of the network. The system retrieves a cone model from the historical trajectories to track multiple intruders. Finally, the system validates the mining results and updates sensors’ reliability scores in a feedback process. In addition, LoRM (Line-on-the-Road Miner) is proposed for trajectory discovery on road networks—mining lines on the roads. LoRM employs a filtering-and-refinement framework to reduce the distance computational overhead on road networks and uses a shortest-path-measure to track intruders. The proposed methods are evaluated with extensive experiments on big datasets. The experimental results show that the proposed methods achieve higher accuracy and efficiency in trajectory mining tasks."	Feb-15	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:11	16:1–16:35		3	9															ACM Digital Library							Cyber-physical system; sensor network; trajectory																																														
8JQU46C8	journalArticle	2009	"Lin Chen; Leneutre, J."	A Game Theoretical Framework on Intrusion Detection in Heterogeneous Networks	IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics and Security		1556-6013	10.1109/TIFS.2009.2019154	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4815406		Jun-09	8/11/2015 12:56	9/2/2015 18:36	8/11/2015 12:56	165-178		2	4															CrossRef																																																					
NNX76VC4	journalArticle	2014	"Moosavi, Hussein; Bui, Francis Minhthang"	A Game-Theoretic Framework for Robust Optimal Intrusion Detection in Wireless Sensor Networks	IEEE Transactions on Information Forensics and Security		"1556-6013, 1556-6021"	10.1109/TIFS.2014.2332816	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6842601		Sep-14	8/11/2015 12:57	9/2/2015 18:36	8/11/2015 12:57	1367-1379		9	9															CrossRef																																																					
KHI8ACEV	conferencePaper	2011	"Van Woensel, William; Casteleyn, Sven; De Troyer, Olga"	A Generic Approach for On-the-fly Adding of Context-aware Features to Existing Websites	Proceedings of the 22Nd ACM Conference on Hypertext and Hypermedia	978-1-4503-0256-2		10.1145/1995966.1995987	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1995966.1995987	"More and more, mobile devices act as personal information managers and are able to obtain rich contextual information on the user's environment. Mobile, context-aware web applications can exploit this information to better address the needs of mobile users. Currently, such websites are either developed separately from their associated desktop-oriented version, or both versions are created simultaneously by employing methodologies that support multi-platform context-aware websites, requiring an extensive engineering effort. While these approaches provide a solution for developing new websites, they go past the plethora of existing websites. To address this issue, we present an approach for enhancing existing websites on-the-fly with context-aware features. We first discuss the requirements for such an adaptation process, and identify applicable adaptation methods to realize context-aware features. Next, we explain our generic approach, which is grounded in the use of semantic information extracted from existing websites. Finally, we present a concrete application of our approach that is based on the SCOUT framework for mobile and context-aware application development."	2011	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:06	143–152							HT '11				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library							client-side adaptation; context-aware; mobile web; semantic web																																														
MPFT9C4U	conferencePaper	2011	"Ficco, Massimo; Romano, Luigi"	A Generic Intrusion Detection and Diagnoser System Based on Complex Event Processing		978-1-4577-1458-0		10.1109/CCP.2011.43	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6061035		Jun-11	8/11/2015 13:08	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:08	275-284											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
ITVG82EI	conferencePaper	2013	"Marchesani, Stefano; Pomante, Luigi; Pugliese, Marco; Santucci, Fortunato"	A Middleware Approach to Provide Security in IEEE 802.15.4 Wireless Sensor Networks		978-1-936968-94-7		10.1109/Mobilware.2013.21	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6775056		Nov-13	8/11/2015 13:12	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:12	85-93											European Alliance for Innovation							CrossRef																																																					
FPUCVBM5	conferencePaper	2010	"Hidaka, Shohei; Yu, Chen"	Analyzing Multimodal Time Series As Dynamical Systems	International Conference on Multimodal Interfaces and the Workshop on Machine Learning for Multimodal Interaction	978-1-4503-0414-6		10.1145/1891903.1891968	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1891903.1891968	"We propose a novel approach to discovering latent structures from multimodal time series. We view a time series as observed data from an underlying dynamical system. In this way, analyzing multimodal time series can be viewed as finding latent structures from dynamical systems. In light this, our approach is based on the concept of generating partition which is the theoretically best symbolization of time series maximizing the information of the underlying original continuous dynamical system. However, generating partition is difficult to achieve for time series without explicit dynamical equations. Different from most previous approaches that attempt to approximate generating partition through various deterministic symbolization processes, our algorithm maintains and estimates a probabilistic distribution over a symbol set for each data point in a time series. To do so, we develop a Bayesian framework for probabilistic symbolization and demonstrate that the approach can be successfully applied to both simulated data and empirical data from multimodal agent-agent interactions. We suggest this unsupervised learning algorithm has a potential to be used in various multimodal datasets as first steps to identify underlying structures between temporal variables."	2010	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:02	53:1–53:8							ICMI-MLMI '10				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library							generating partition; multi-agent communication; multi-stream time series; symbol dynamics																																														
XQEWRGNF	conferencePaper	1998	"Balasubramaniyan, J.S.; Garcia-Fernandez, J.O.; Isacoff, D.; Spafford, E.; Zamboni, D."	An architecture for intrusion detection using autonomous agents	"Computer Security Applications Conference, 1998. Proceedings. 14th Annual"			10.1109/CSAC.1998.738563		"The intrusion detection system architectures commonly used in commercial and research systems have a number of problems that limit their configurability, scalability or efficiency. The most common shortcoming in the existing architectures is that they are built around a single monolithic entity that does most of the data collection and processing. In this paper, we review our architecture for a distributed intrusion detection system based on multiple independent entities working collectively. We call these entities autonomous agents. This approach solves some of the problems previously mentioned. We present the motivation and description of the approach, partial results obtained from an early prototype, a discussion of design and implementation issues, and directions for future work"	Dec-98	7/24/2014 19:08	7/24/2014 19:08		13-24																		IEEE Xplore				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\NGXWGXI4\abs_all.html; C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\EM2T7RGS\Balasubramaniyan et al. - 1998 - An architecture for intrusion detection using auto.pdf		strategy	Authorization; autonomous agents; Contracts; data collection; data processing; distributed intrusion detection system; Ear; Event detection; intrusion detection; intrusion detection system architectures; Laboratories; MONOS devices; multi-agent systems; multiple independent entities; Prototypes; Read only memory; security of data; software agents																															"Computer Security Applications Conference, 1998. Proceedings. 14th Annual"															
Z5DV6QRW	conferencePaper	2009	"Ou, Xinming; Rajagopalan, Siva Raj; Sakthivelmurugan, Sakthiyuvaraja"	An Empirical Approach to Modeling Uncertainty in Intrusion Analysis		978-1-4244-5327-6 978-0-7695-3919-5		10.1109/ACSAC.2009.53	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=5380706		Dec-09	8/11/2015 13:09	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:09	494-503											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
73BH7J7Z	conferencePaper	2006	"Tulone, Daniela; Madden, Samuel"	An Energy-efficient Querying Framework in Sensor Networks for Detecting Node Similarities	Proceedings of the 9th ACM International Symposium on Modeling Analysis and Simulation of Wireless and Mobile Systems	978-1-59593-477-2		10.1145/1164717.1164768	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1164717.1164768	"We propose an energy-efficient framework, called SAF, for approximate querying and clustering of nodes in a sensor network. SAF uses simple time series forecasting models to predict sensor readings. The idea is to build these local models at each node, transmit them to the root of the network (the ""sink""), and use them to approximately answer user queries. Our approach dramatically reduces communication relative to previous approaches for querying sensor networks by exploiting properties of these local models, since each sensor communicates with the sink only when its local model varies due to changes in the underlying data distribution. In our experimental results performed on a trace of real data, we observed on average about 150 message transmissions from each sensor over a week (including the learning phase) to correctly predict temperatures to within +/- 0.5°C.SAF also provides a mechanism to detect data similarities between nodes and organize nodes into clusters at the sink at no additional communication cost. This is again achieved by exploiting properties of our local time series models, and by means of a novel definition of data similarity between nodes that is based not on raw data but on the prediction values. Our clustering algorithm is both very efficient and provably optimal in the number of clusters. Our clusters have several interesting features: first, they can capture similarity between far away nodes that are not geographically adjacent; second, cluster membership to variations in sensors' local models; third, nodes within a cluster are not required to track the membership of other nodes in the cluster. We present a number of simulation-based experimental results that demonstrate these properties of SAF."	2006	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:53	191–300							MSWiM '06				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library							data collection; data stream; energy; models; query; sensor networks																																														
UCGWT4IW	conferencePaper	2006	"Orebaugh, Angela"	An Instant Messaging Intrusion Detection System Framework: Using character frequency analysis for authorship identification and validation		978-1-4244-0174-1		10.1109/CCST.2006.313445	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4105332		Oct-06	8/11/2015 12:57	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 12:57	160-172						An Instant Messaging Intrusion Detection System Framework					IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
ASARW2W5	conferencePaper	2010	"Chang, Katharine; Shin, Kang G."	Application-Layer Intrusion Detection in MANETs		978-1-4244-5509-6		10.1109/HICSS.2010.65	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=5428421		2010	8/11/2015 13:11	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:11	10-Jan											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
JX8SPZSU	journalArticle	2012	"Singh, Indu; Kumar, Manoj"	A Proposed Model for Data Warehouse User Behaviour Using Intrusion Detection System	SIGSOFT Softw. Eng. Notes		0163-5948	10.1145/2382756.2382771	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2382756.2382771	"Data Warehouse (DW) systems maintain sensitive and crucial information, which is integrated from various heterogenous sources of organization. With the ever increasing deployment and usage of networks, these systems are becoming more vulnerable to malicious attacks. With the increased number of attacks, intrusion detection has become vital part of Information Security. In this paper, we have proposed a model for analyzing and detecting anomalous events based on user behavior analysis through usage patterns, user profiles and session management. After monitoring the events in the system, if any intrusion activity occurs, then alerts are issued to system administrators. Since a user profile is not necessarily fixed but rather it evolves with changing time, so a dynamic user behavior modeling is represented as a sequence of events and combination of fact and dimension tables accessed by the users. In this way, DW systems may be protected by the malicious attacks."	Nov-12	7/28/2014 23:09	7/28/2014 23:09	7/28/2014 23:09	1–7		6	37															ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\WACIT9W5\Singh and Kumar - 2012 - A Proposed Model for Data Warehouse User Behaviour.pdf		strategy	data warehouse; Information security; intrusion detection system; user behaviour																																														
TQIZ9H9G	conferencePaper	2009	"Powell, Michael D.; Biswas, Arijit; Gupta, Shantanu; Mukherjee, Shubhendu S."	Architectural Core Salvaging in a Multi-core Processor for Hard-error Tolerance	Proceedings of the 36th Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture	978-1-60558-526-0		10.1145/1555754.1555769	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1555754.1555769	"The incidence of hard errors in CPUs is a challenge for future multicore designs due to increasing total core area. Even if the location and nature of hard errors are known a priori, either at manufacture-time or in the field, cores with such errors must be disabled in the absence of hard-error tolerance. While caches, with their regular and repetitive structures, are easily covered against hard errors by providing spare arrays or spare lines, structures within a core are neither as regular nor as repetitive. Previous work has proposed microarchitectural core salvaging to exploit structural redundancy within a core and maintain functionality in the presence of hard errors. Unfortunately microarchitectural salvaging introduces complexity and may provide only limited coverage of core area against hard errors due to a lack of natural redundancy in the core. This paper makes a case for architectural core salvaging. We observe that even if some individual cores cannot execute certain operations, a CPU die can be instruction-set-architecture (ISA) compliant, that is execute all of the instructions required by its ISA, by exploiting natural cross-core redundancy. We propose using hardware to migrate offending threads to another core that can execute the operation. Architectural core salvaging can cover a large core area against faults, and be implemented by leveraging known techniques that minimize changes to the microarchitecture. We show it is possible to optimize architectural core salvaging such that the performance on a faulty die approaches that of a fault-free die--assuring significantly better performance than core disabling for many workloads and no worse performance than core disabling for the remainder."	2009	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:15	93–104							ISCA '09				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library							core salvaging; hard errors; redundancy; reliability																																														
QCQJ975G	conferencePaper	2013	"Hamilton, John A."	Architecture-based network simulation for cyber security		978-1-4799-3950-3 978-1-4799-2077-8		10.1109/WSC.2013.6721660	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6721660		Dec-13	8/11/2015 13:18	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:18	2914-2922											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
99DVW8JA	journalArticle	2006	"Dobson, Simon; Denazis, Spyros; Fernández, Antonio; Gaïti, Dominique; Gelenbe, Erol; Massacci, Fabio; Nixon, Paddy; Saffre, Fabrice; Schmidt, Nikita; Zambonelli, Franco"	A Survey of Autonomic Communications	ACM Trans. Auton. Adapt. Syst.		1556-4665	10.1145/1186778.1186782	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1186778.1186782	"Autonomic communications seek to improve the ability of network and services to cope with unpredicted change, including changes in topology, load, task, the physical and logical characteristics of the networks that can be accessed, and so forth. Broad-ranging autonomic solutions require designers to account for a range of end-to-end issues affecting programming models, network and contextual modeling and reasoning, decentralised algorithms, trust acquisition and maintenance---issues whose solutions may draw on approaches and results from a surprisingly broad range of disciplines. We survey the current state of autonomic communications research and identify significant emerging trends and techniques."	Dec-06	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:02	223–259		2	1															ACM Digital Library							Autonomic; communication																																														
ZQIRPE7V	journalArticle	2014	"Medina, Violeta; García, Juan Manuel"	A Survey of Migration Mechanisms of Virtual Machines	ACM Comput. Surv.		0360-0300	10.1145/2492705	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2492705	"In the virtualization area, replication has been considered as a mechanism to provide high availability. A high-availability system should be active most of the time, and this is the reason that its design should consider almost zero downtime and a minimal human intervention if a recovery process is demanded. Several migration and replication mechanisms have been developed to provide high availability inside virtualized environments. In this article, a survey of migration mechanisms is reported. These approaches are classified in three main classes: process migration, memory migration, and suspend/resume migration."	Jan-14	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:07	30:1–30:33		3	46															ACM Digital Library							High availability; migration; replication; virtualization; virtual machine																																														
R3MHPB7U	conferencePaper	2013	"Ku, Chih-Hao; Leroy, Gondy"	Automated Crime Report Analysis and Classification for e-Government and Decision Support	Proceedings of the 14th Annual International Conference on Digital Government Research	978-1-4503-2057-3		10.1145/2479724.2479732	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2479724.2479732	"With an increasing number of anonymous crime tips and reports being filed and digitized, it is generally difficult for crime analysts to process and analyze crime reports efficiently. We are developing a decision support system (DSS), combining Natural Language Processing (NLP) techniques, a document similarity measure, and machine learning, i.e., a Naïve Bayes' classifier, to support crime analysis and classify which crime reports discuss the same and different crime. The DSS is developed with text mining techniques and evaluated with an active crime analyst. We report here on an experiment that includes two datasets with 40 and 60 crime reports and 16 different types of crimes for each dataset. The results show that our system achieved the highest classification accuracy (94.82%), while the crime analyst's classification accuracy (93.74%) is slightly lower."	2013	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:11	18–27							dg.o '13				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library							classification; natural language processing; similarity measures																																														
IAAA87CV	conferencePaper	2006	"Massicotte, Frederic; Gagnon, Francois; Labiche, Yvan; Briand, Lionel; Couture, Mathieu"	Automatic Evaluation of Intrusion Detection Systems		978-0-7695-2716-1		10.1109/ACSAC.2006.15	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4041181		Dec-06	8/11/2015 13:08	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:08	361-370											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
KCAXWCFD	journalArticle	2006	"Baker, Zachary; Prasanna, Viktor"	Automatic Synthesis of Efficient Intrusion Detection Systems on FPGAs	IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing		1545-5971	10.1109/TDSC.2006.44	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4012642		Oct-06	8/11/2015 13:01	9/22/2015 15:13	8/11/2015 13:01	289-300		4	3															CrossRef																																																					
2MDM74S4	conferencePaper	2009	"Li, Zhichun; Goyal, Anup; Chen, Yan; Paxson, Vern"	Automating Analysis of Large-scale Botnet Probing Events	"Proceedings of the 4th International Symposium on Information, Computer, and Communications Security"	978-1-60558-394-5		10.1145/1533057.1533063	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1533057.1533063	"Botnets dominate today's attack landscape. In this work we investigate ways to analyze collections of malicious probing traffic in order to understand the significance of large-scale ""botnet probes"". In such events, an entire collection of remote hosts together probes the address space monitored by a sensor in some sort of coordinated fashion. Our goal is to develop methodologies by which sites receiving such probes can infer---using purely local observation---information about the probing activity: What scanning strategies does the probing employ? Is this an attack that specifically targets the site, or is the site only incidentally probed as part of a larger, indiscriminant attack? Our analysis draws upon extensive honeynet data to explore the prevalence of different types of scanning, including properties such as trend, uniformity, coordination, and darknet avoidance. In addition, we design schemes to extrapolate the global properties of scanning events (e.g., total population and target scope) as inferred from the limited local view of a honeynet. Cross-validating with data from DShield shows that our inferences exhibit promising accuracy."	2009	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:06	11–22							ASIACCS '09				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library							botnet; global property extrapolation; honeynet; scan strategy inference; situational awareness; statistical inference																																														
RC5N6KN3	conferencePaper	2006	"Strasser, Mario; Vogt, Harald"	Autonomous and Distributed Node Recovery in Wireless Sensor Networks	Proceedings of the Fourth ACM Workshop on Security of Ad Hoc and Sensor Networks	978-1-59593-554-0		10.1145/1180345.1180360	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1180345.1180360	"Intrusion or misbehaviour detection systems are an important and widely accepted security tool in computer and wireless sensor networks. Their aim is to detect misbehaving or faulty nodes in order to take appropriate countermeasures, thus limiting the damage caused by adversaries as well as by hard or software faults. So far, however, once detected, misbehaving nodes have just been isolated from the rest of the sensor network and hence are no longer usable by running applications. In the presence of an adversary or software faults, this proceeding will inevitably lead to an early and complete loss of the whole network.For this reason, we propose to no longer expel misbehaving nodes, but to recover them into normal operation. In this paper, we address this problem and present a formal specification of what is considered a secure and correct node recovery algorithm together with a distributed algorithm that meets these properties. We discuss its requirements on the soft- and hardware of a node and show how they can be fulfilled with current and upcoming technologies. The algorithm is evaluated analytically as well as by means of extensive simulations, and the findings are compared to the outcome of a real implementation for the BTnode sensor platform. The results show that recovering sensor nodes is an expensive, though feasible and worthwhile task. Moreover, the proposed program code update algorithm is not only secure but also fair and robust."	2006	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:06	113–122							SASN '06				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library							intrusion detection; node recovery; sensor networks; wireless																																														
572I7TN8	conferencePaper	2008	"Becchi, Michela; Franklin, Mark; Crowley, Patrick"	A workload for evaluating deep packet inspection architectures		978-1-4244-2777-2		10.1109/IISWC.2008.4636093	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4636093		Oct-08	8/11/2015 13:04	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:04	79-89											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
ANDVVI6E	journalArticle	2006	"Estan, C.; Varghese, G.; Fisk, M."	Bitmap Algorithms for Counting Active Flows on High-Speed Links	IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking		1063-6692	10.1109/TNET.2006.882836	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=1709947		Oct-06	8/11/2015 12:57	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 12:57	925-937		5	14															CrossRef																																																					
MG696TSD	journalArticle	2011	"Xiang, Guang; Hong, Jason; Rose, Carolyn P.; Cranor, Lorrie"	CANTINA+: A Feature-Rich Machine Learning Framework for Detecting Phishing Web Sites	ACM Trans. Inf. Syst. Secur.		1094-9224	10.1145/2019599.2019606	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2019599.2019606	"Phishing is a plague in cyberspace. Typically, phish detection methods either use human-verified URL blacklists or exploit Web page features via machine learning techniques. However, the former is frail in terms of new phish, and the latter suffers from the scarcity of effective features and the high false positive rate (FP). To alleviate those problems, we propose a layered anti-phishing solution that aims at (1) exploiting the expressiveness of a rich set of features with machine learning to achieve a high true positive rate (TP) on novel phish, and (2) limiting the FP to a low level via filtering algorithms. Specifically, we proposed CANTINA+, the most comprehensive feature-based approach in the literature including eight novel features, which exploits the HTML Document Object Model (DOM), search engines and third party services with machine learning techniques to detect phish. Moreover, we designed two filters to help reduce FP and achieve runtime speedup. The first is a near-duplicate phish detector that uses hashing to catch highly similar phish. The second is a login form filter, which directly classifies Web pages with no identified login form as legitimate. We extensively evaluated CANTINA+ with two methods on a diverse spectrum of corpora with 8118 phish and 4883 legitimate Web pages. In the randomized evaluation, CANTINA+ achieved over 92% TP on unique testing phish and over 99% TP on near-duplicate testing phish, and about 0.4% FP with 10% training phish. In the time-based evaluation, CANTINA+ also achieved over 92% TP on unique testing phish, over 99% TP on near-duplicate testing phish, and about 1.4% FP under 20% training phish with a two-week sliding window. Capable of achieving 0.4% FP and over 92% TP, our CANTINA+ has been demonstrated to be a competitive anti-phishing solution."	Sep-11	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:09	21:1–21:28		2	14			CANTINA+												ACM Digital Library							Anti-phishing; information retrieval; machine learning																																														
IP3SBSE4	journalArticle	2015	"Gill, Phillipa; Crete-Nishihata, Masashi; Dalek, Jakub; Goldberg, Sharon; Senft, Adam; Wiseman, Greg"	Characterizing Web Censorship Worldwide: Another Look at the OpenNet Initiative Data	ACM Trans. Web		1559-1131	10.1145/2700339	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2700339	"In this study, we take another look at 5 years of web censorship data gathered by the OpenNet Initiative in 77 countries using user-based testing with locally relevant content. Prior to our work, this data had been analyzed with little automation, focusing on what content had been blocked, rather than how blocking was carried out. In this study, we use more rigorous automation to obtain a longitudinal, global view of the technical means used for web censorship. We also identify blocking that had been missed in prior analyses. Our results point to considerable variability in the technologies used for web censorship, across countries, time, and types of content, and even across ISPs in the same country. In addition to characterizing web censorship in countries that, thus far, have eluded technical analysis, we also discuss the implications of our observations on the design of future network measurement platforms and circumvention technologies."	Jan-15	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:18	4:1–4:29		1	9			Characterizing Web Censorship Worldwide												ACM Digital Library							Censorship; network measurement																																														
DF9CECBD	journalArticle	2009	"Zhu, Ye; Bettati, Riccardo"	Compromising Anonymous Communication Systems Using Blind Source Separation	ACM Trans. Inf. Syst. Secur.		1094-9224	10.1145/1609956.1609964	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1609956.1609964	"We propose a class of anonymity attacks to both wired and wireless anonymity networks. These attacks are based on the blind source separation algorithms widely used to recover individual signals from mixtures of signals in statistical signal processing. Since the philosophy behind the design of current anonymity networks is to mix traffic or to hide in crowds, the proposed anonymity attacks are very effective. The flow separation attack proposed for wired anonymity networks can separate the traffic in a mix network. Our experiments show that this attack is effective and scalable. By combining the flow separation method with frequency spectrum matching, a passive attacker can derive the traffic map of the mix network. We use a nontrivial network to show that the combined attack works. The proposed anonymity attacks for wireless networks can identify nodes in fully anonymized wireless networks using collections of very simple sensors. Based on a time series of counts of anonymous packets provided by the sensors, we estimate the number of nodes with the use of principal component analysis. We then proceed to separate the collected packet data into traffic flows that, with help of the spatial diversity in the available sensors, can be used to estimate the location of the wireless nodes. Our simulation experiments indicate that the estimators show high accuracy and high confidence for anonymized TCP traffic. Additional experiments indicate that the estimators perform very well in anonymous wireless networks that use traffic padding."	Nov-09	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:10	8:1–8:31		1	13															ACM Digital Library							Anonymous communication; blind source separation; location privacy																																														
K2VFAV5M	conferencePaper	2010	"Shin, Seungwon; Gu, Guofei"	Conficker and Beyond: A Large-scale Empirical Study	Proceedings of the 26th Annual Computer Security Applications Conference	978-1-4503-0133-6		10.1145/1920261.1920285	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1920261.1920285	"Conficker [26] is the most recent widespread, well-known worm/bot. According to several reports [16, 28], it has infected about 7 million to 15 million hosts and the victims are still increasing even now. In this paper, we analyze Conficker infections at a large scale, including about 25 millions victims, and study various interesting aspects about this state-of-the-art malware. By analyzing Conficker, we intend to understand current and new trends in malware propagation, which could be very helpful in predicting future malware trends and providing insights for future malware defense. We observe that Conficker has some very different victim distribution patterns compared to many previous generation worms/botnets, suggesting that new malware spreading models and defense strategies are likely needed. Furthermore, we intend to determine how well a reputation-based blacklisting approach can perform when faced with new malware threats such as Conficker. We cross-check several DNS blacklists and IP/AS reputation data from Dshield [6] and FIRE [7], and our evaluation shows that unlike a previous study [18] which shows that a blacklist-based approach can detect most bots, these reputation-based approaches did relatively poorly for Conficker. This raised the question, how can we improve and complement existing reputation-based techniques to prepare for future malware defense? Finally, we look into some insights for defenders. We show that neighborhood watch is a surprisingly effective approach in the Conficker case. This suggests that security alert sharing/correlation (particularly among neighborhood networks) could be a promising approach and play a more important role for future malware defense."	2010	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:59	151–160						Conficker and Beyond	ACSAC '10				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library																																																					
9NEUZPUX	journalArticle	2015	"Baur, Tobias; Mehlmann, Gregor; Damian, Ionut; Lingenfelser, Florian; Wagner, Johannes; Lugrin, Birgit; André, Elisabeth; Gebhard, Patrick"	Context-Aware Automated Analysis and Annotation of Social Human–Agent Interactions	ACM Trans. Interact. Intell. Syst.		2160-6455	10.1145/2764921	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2764921	"The outcome of interpersonal interactions depends not only on the contents that we communicate verbally, but also on nonverbal social signals. Because a lack of social skills is a common problem for a significant number of people, serious games and other training environments have recently become the focus of research. In this work, we present NovA (Nonverbal behavior Analyzer), a system that analyzes and facilitates the interpretation of social signals automatically in a bidirectional interaction with a conversational agent. It records data of interactions, detects relevant social cues, and creates descriptive statistics for the recorded data with respect to the agent's behavior and the context of the situation. This enhances the possibilities for researchers to automatically label corpora of human--agent interactions and to give users feedback on strengths and weaknesses of their social behavior."	Jun-15	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:11	11:1–11:33		2	5															ACM Digital Library							automated behavior analysis; interaction design; serious games; Social cue recognition; virtual job interviews																																														
QKJ6JHEZ	conferencePaper	2007	"Sterne, Daniel; Lawler, Geoffrey; Gopaul, Richard; Rivera, Brian; Marcus, Kelvin; Kruus, Peter"	Countering False Accusations and Collusion in the Detection of In-Band Wormholes		978-0-7695-3060-4		10.1109/ACSAC.2007.41	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4412993		Dec-07	8/11/2015 12:56	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 12:56	243-256											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
R48I289I	journalArticle	2011	"Kamra, Ashish; Bertino, Elisa"	Design and Implementation of an Intrusion Response System for Relational Databases	IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering		1041-4347	10.1109/TKDE.2010.151	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=5560655		Jun-11	8/11/2015 12:57	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 12:57	875-888		6	23															CrossRef																																																					
F4KJT33W	conferencePaper	2009	"Szymczyk, Miroslaw"	Detecting Botnets in Computer Networks Using Multi-agent Technology		978-0-7695-3674-3		10.1109/DepCoS-RELCOMEX.2009.46	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=5261007		2009	8/11/2015 13:08	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:08	192-201											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
MMMQ6EWQ	conferencePaper	2013	"Morris, Thomas H.; Jones, Bryan A.; Vaughn, Rayford B.; Dandass, Yoginder S."	Deterministic Intrusion Detection Rules for MODBUS Protocols		978-1-4673-5933-7 978-0-7695-4892-0		10.1109/HICSS.2013.174	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6480055		Jan-13	8/11/2015 13:11	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:11	1773-1781											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
5U7PT8D9	journalArticle	2011	"Fung, Carol J; Zhang, Jie; Aib, Issam; Boutaba, Raouf"	Dirichlet-Based Trust Management for Effective Collaborative Intrusion Detection Networks	IEEE Transactions on Network and Service Management		1932-4537	10.1109/TNSM.2011.050311.100028	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=5871350		Jun-11	8/11/2015 12:57	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 12:57	79-91		2	8															CrossRef																																																					
PDIW6NWW	journalArticle	2011	"Bu, Shengrong; Yu, F. Richard; Liu, Xiaoping P.; Mason, Peter; Tang, Helen"	Distributed Combined Authentication and Intrusion Detection With Data Fusion in High-Security Mobile Ad Hoc Networks	IEEE Transactions on Vehicular Technology		"0018-9545, 1939-9359"	10.1109/TVT.2010.2103098	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=5678662		Mar-11	8/11/2015 13:02	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:02	1025-1036		3	60															CrossRef																																																					
ZIE85S8J	conferencePaper	2014	"Schomp, Kyle; Allman, Mark; Rabinovich, Michael"	DNS Resolvers Considered Harmful	Proceedings of the 13th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks	978-1-4503-3256-9		10.1145/2670518.2673881	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2670518.2673881	"The Domain Name System (DNS) is a critical component of the Internet infrastructure that has many security vulnerabilities. In particular, shared DNS resolvers are a notorious security weak spot in the system. We propose an unorthodox approach for tackling vulnerabilities in shared DNS resolvers: removing shared DNS resolvers entirely and leaving recursive resolution to the clients. We show that the two primary costs of this approach---loss of performance and an increase in system load---are modest and therefore conclude that this approach is beneficial for strengthening the DNS by reducing the attack surface."	2014	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:09	16:1–16:7							HotNets-XIII				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library																																																					
9JJVD8H8	conferencePaper	2014	"Kourai, Kenichi; Nakamura, Kousuke"	Efficient VM Introspection in KVM and Performance Comparison with Xen		978-1-4799-6474-1 978-1-4799-6473-4		10.1109/PRDC.2014.33	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6974789		Nov-14	8/11/2015 13:04	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:04	192-202											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
967SH5DM	conferencePaper	2010	"Park, Jong Chun; Crandall, Jedidiah R."	Empirical Study of a National-Scale Distributed Intrusion Detection System: Backbone-Level Filtering of HTML Responses in China		978-1-4244-7261-1		10.1109/ICDCS.2010.46	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=5541676		2010	8/11/2015 12:58	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 12:58	315-326						Empirical Study of a National-Scale Distributed Intrusion Detection System					IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
VNURRVXU	conferencePaper	2011	"Kaur, P.; Rattan, D.; Bhardwaj, A. K."	Enhancement of Fault Tolerance of Intrusion Detection System Using AES and DES Based Heart Beat Events	Proceedings of the International Conference &#38; Workshop on Emerging Trends in Technology	978-1-4503-0449-8		10.1145/1980022.1980088	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1980022.1980088	"In accordance with the increasing importance of intrusion detection systems (IDS), users justifiably demand the trustworthiness of the IDS. However, IDS themselves are prone to various attacks and it becomes the natural primary target of hostile attacks with the aim of disabling the detection feature and allowing an attacker to operate without being detected. This paper suggests that intrusion detection system (IDS) must be fault tolerant; otherwise, the intruder may first subvert the IDS then attack the target system at will. Making an IDS fault tolerant [2] is a challenging task. The aim of this research paper is to enhance the fault tolerance of IDS using AES and DES based heart beat events. Brute Force attack has been simulated and the effectiveness of encrypted heartbeat event based fault tolerance for Intrusion Detection System is evaluated."	2011	7/28/2014 23:06	7/28/2014 23:06	7/28/2014 23:06	292–297							ICWET '11				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\PSXTK62I\Kaur et al. - 2011 - Enhancement of Fault Tolerance of Intrusion Detect.pdf		enhancement	AES; DES; fault tolerance; heartbeat message; integrity checking; intrusion detection system																																														
5M3Q7QAW	journalArticle	2010	"Ficara, Domenico; Di Pietro, Andrea; Giordano, Stefano; Procissi, Gregorio; Vitucci, Fabio"	Enhancing Counting Bloom Filters Through Huffman-coded Multilayer Structures	IEEE/ACM Trans. Netw.		1063-6692	10.1109/TNET.2010.2055243	http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TNET.2010.2055243	"Bloom Filters are efficient randomized data structures for membership queries on a set with a certain known false positive probability. Counting Bloom Filters (CBFs) allow the same operation on dynamic sets that can be updated via insertions and deletions with larger memory requirements. This paper first presents a simple tight upper bound for counters overflow probability in CBFs, which is adopted in the design of more efficient CBFs. On the basis of such theoretical achievements, we introduce the idea of a hierarchical structure as well as the use of Huffman code to improve standard CBFs in terms of fast access and limited memory consumption (up to 50% of memory saving). The target could be the implementation of the compressed data structures in the small (but fast) local memory or ""on-chip SRAM"" of devices such as network processors. As an application of our algorithms, an anti-evasion system is finally proposed."	Dec-10	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:18	1977–1987		6	18															ACM Digital Library							counting bloom filter (CBF); evasion; hashing; Huffman coding; multilayer structure; network processor																																														
QS3W5MDG	journalArticle	2008	"Ryu, Young U.; Rhee, Hyeun-Suk"	Evaluation of Intrusion Detection Systems Under a Resource Constraint	ACM Trans. Inf. Syst. Secur.		1094-9224	10.1145/1380564.1380566	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1380564.1380566	"An intrusion detection system plays an important role in a firm's overall security protection. Its main purpose is to identify potentially intrusive events and alert the security personnel to the danger. A typical intrusion detection system, however, is known to be imperfect in detection of intrusive events, resulting in high false-alarm rates. Nevertheless, current intrusion detection models unreasonably assume that upon alerts raised by a system, an information security officer responds to all alarms without any delay and avoids damages of hostile activities. This assumption of responding to all alarms with no time lag is often impracticable. As a result, the benefit of an intrusion detection system can be overestimated by current intrusion detection models. In this article, we extend previous models by including an information security officer's alarm inspection under a constraint as a part of the process in determining the optimal intrusion detection policy. Given a potentially hostile environment for a firm, in which the intrusion rates and costs associated with intrusion and security officers' inspection can be estimated, we outline a framework to establish the optimal operating points for intrusion detection systems under security officers' inspection constraint. The optimal solution to the model will provide not only a basis of better evaluation of intrusion detection systems but also useful insights into operations of intrusion detection systems. The firm can estimate expected benefits for running intrusion detection systems and establish a basis for increase in security personnel to relax security officers' inspection constraint."	Jul-08	7/24/2014 18:36	7/24/2014 18:36	7/24/2014 18:36	20:1–20:24		4	11															ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\AF9FTF52\Ryu and Rhee - 2008 - Evaluation of Intrusion Detection Systems Under a .pdf		evaluation	computer security; intrusion detection; optimal inspection rates; optimal operating points																																														
J5IBVX6J	conferencePaper	2015	"Koutra, Danai; Bennett, Paul N.; Horvitz, Eric"	Events and Controversies: Influences of a Shocking News Event on Information Seeking	Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on World Wide Web	978-1-4503-3469-3			http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2736277.2741099	"It has been suggested that online search and retrieval contributes to the intellectual isolation of users within their preexisting ideologies, where people's prior views are strengthened and alternative viewpoints are infrequently encountered. This so-called ""filter bubble"" phenomenon has been called out as especially detrimental when it comes to dialog among people on controversial, emotionally charged topics, such as the labeling of genetically modified food, the right to bear arms, the death penalty, and online privacy. We seek to identify and study information-seeking behavior and access to alternative versus reinforcing viewpoints following shocking, emotional, and large-scale news events. We choose for a case study to analyze search and browsing on gun control/rights, a strongly polarizing topic for both citizens and leaders of the United States. We study the period of time preceding and following a mass shooting to understand how its occurrence, follow-on discussions, and debate may have been linked to changes in the patterns of searching and browsing. We employ information-theoretic measures to quantify the diversity of Web domains of interest to users and understand the browsing patterns of users. We use these measures to characterize the influence of news events on these web search and browsing patterns."	2015	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:03	614–624						Events and Controversies	WWW '15				International World Wide Web Conferences Steering Committee	"Republic and Canton of Geneva, Switzerland"						ACM Digital Library							controversies; filter bubble; log / behavioral analysis																																														
7PQRI2BU	conferencePaper	2006	"Yang, Junfeng; Sar, Can; Engler, Dawson"	"EXPLODE: A Lightweight, General System for Finding Serious Storage System Errors"	Proceedings of the 7th Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation	978-1-931971-47-8			http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=1298455.1298469	"Storage systems such as file systems, databases, and RAID systems have a simple, basic contract: you give them data, they do not lose or corrupt it. Often they store the only copy, making its irrevocable loss almost arbitrarily bad. Unfortunately, their code is exceptionally hard to get right, since it must correctly recover from any crash at any program point, no matter how their state was smeared across volatile and persistent memory. This paper describes EXPLODE, a system that makes it easy to systematically check real storage systems for errors. It takes user-written, potentially system-specific checkers and uses them to drive a storage system into tricky corner cases, including crash recovery errors. EXPLODE uses a novel adaptation of ideas from model checking, a comprehensive, heavy-weight formal verification technique, that makes its checking more systematic (and hopefully more effective) than a pure testing approach while being just as lightweight. EXPLODE is effective. It found serious bugs in a broad range of real storage systems (without requiring source code): three version control systems, Berkeley DB, an NFS implementation, ten file systems, a RAID system, and the popular VMware GSX virtual machine. We found bugs in every system we checked, 36 bugs in total, typically with little effort."	2006	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:02	131–146						EXPLODE	OSDI '06				USENIX Association	"Berkeley, CA, USA"						ACM Digital Library																																																					
RXDIM78R	conferencePaper	2009	"Vassilevska, Virginia; Williams, Ryan"	"Finding, Minimizing, and Counting Weighted Subgraphs"	Proceedings of the Forty-first Annual ACM Symposium on Theory of Computing	978-1-60558-506-2		10.1145/1536414.1536477	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1536414.1536477	"For a pattern graph H on k nodes, we consider the problems of finding and counting the number of (not necessarily induced) copies of H in a given large graph G on n nodes, as well as finding minimum weight copies in both node-weighted and edge-weighted graphs. Our results include: The number of copies of an H with an independent set of size s can be computed exactly in O*(2s nk-s+3) time. A minimum weight copy of such an H (with arbitrary real weights on nodes and edges) can be found in O(4s+o(s) nk-s+3) time. (The O* notation omits (k) factors.) These algorithms rely on fast algorithms for computing the permanent of a k x n matrix, over rings and semirings. The number of copies of any H having minimum (or maximum) node-weight (with arbitrary real weights on nodes) can be found in O(nω k/3 + n2k/3+o(1)) time, where ω < 2.4 is the matrix multiplication exponent and k is divisible by 3. Similar results hold for other values of k. Also, the number of copies having exactly a prescribed weight can be found within this time. These algorithms extend the technique of Czumaj and Lingas (SODA 2007) and give a new (algorithmic) application of multiparty communication complexity. Finding an edge-weighted triangle of weight exactly 0 in general graphs requires Ω(n2.5-ε) time for all ε > 0, unless the 3SUM problem on N numbers can be solved in O(N2 - ε) time. This suggests that the edge-weighted problem is much harder than its node-weighted version."	2009	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:09	455–464							STOC '09				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library							3sum; cliques; paths; subgraph isomorphism; weighted graph																																														
DWENJAKC	journalArticle	2013	"Amoroso, Edward G."	From the Enterprise Perimeter to a Mobility-Enabled Secure Cloud	IEEE Security & Privacy		1540-7993	10.1109/MSP.2013.8	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6427810		Jan-13	8/11/2015 13:13	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:13	23-31		1	11															CrossRef																																																					
G92WNKCP	conferencePaper	2010	"Valamehr, Jonathan; Tiwari, Mohit; Sherwood, Timothy; Kastner, Ryan; Huffmire, Ted; Irvine, Cynthia; Levin, Timothy"	Hardware Assistance for Trustworthy Systems Through 3-D Integration	Proceedings of the 26th Annual Computer Security Applications Conference	978-1-4503-0133-6		10.1145/1920261.1920292	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1920261.1920292	"Hardware resources are abundant; state-of-the-art processors have over one billion transistors. Yet for a variety of reasons, specialized hardware functions for high assurance processing are seldom (i.e., a couple of features per vendor over twenty years) integrated into these commodity processors, despite a small flurry of late (e.g., ARM TrustZone, Intel VT-x/VT-d and AMD-V/AMD-Vi, Intel TXT and AMD SVM, and Intel AES-NI). Furthermore, as chips increase in complexity, trustworthy processing of sensitive information can become increasingly difficult to achieve due to extensive on-chip resource sharing and the lack of corresponding protection mechanisms. In this paper, we introduce a method to enhance the security of commodity integrated circuits, using minor modifications, in conjunction with a separate integrated circuit that can provide monitoring, access control, and other useful security functions. We introduce a new architecture using a separate control plane, stacked using 3D integration, that allows for the function and economics of specialized security mechanisms, not available from a co-processor alone, to be integrated with the underlying commodity computing hardware. We first describe a general methodology to modify the host computation plane by attaching an optional control plane using 3-D integration. In a developed example we show how this approach can increase system trustworthiness, through mitigating the cache-based side channel problem by routing signals from the computation plane through a cache monitor in the 3-D control plane. We show that the overhead of our example application, in terms of area, delay and performance impact, is negligible."	2010	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:17	199–210							ACSAC '10				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library																																																					
HFT6DRKE	conferencePaper	2011	"Nguyen, Hai; Apon, Amy"	Hierarchical Performance Measurement and Modeling of the Linux File System	Proceedings of the 2Nd ACM/SPEC International Conference on Performance Engineering	978-1-4503-0519-8		10.1145/1958746.1958761	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1958746.1958761	"File systems are very important components in a computer system. File system simulation can help to predict the performance of new system designs. It offers the advantages of the flexibility of modeling and the cost and time savings when utilizing simulation instead of full implementation. Being able to predict end-to-end file system performance against a pre-defined workload can help system designers to make decisions that could affect their entire product line, affecting several million dollars of investment. This paper presents a detailed simulation-based performance model of the Linux ext3 file system. The model is developed using Colored Petri Nets. A performance study using the model shows that the obtained results are close to the expected behavior of the real file system. The model shows that file system parameters have significant impact on the performance of the I/O when compared to the parameters of the disk subsystem."	2011	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:02	73–84							ICPE '11				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library																																																					
FTD99AND	conferencePaper	2014	"Biedermann, Sebastian; Katzenbeisser, Stefan; Szefer, Jakub"	Hot-hardening: Getting More out of Your Security Settings	Proceedings of the 30th Annual Computer Security Applications Conference	978-1-4503-3005-3		10.1145/2664243.2664246	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2664243.2664246	"Applying optimized security settings to applications is a difficult and laborious task. Especially in cloud computing, where virtual servers with various pre-installed software packages are leased, selecting optimized security settings is very difficult. In particular, optimized security settings are not identical in every setup. They depend on characteristics of the setup, on the ways an application is used or on other applications running on the same system. Configuring optimized settings given these interdependencies is a complex and time-consuming task. In this work, we present an autonomous agent which improves security settings of applications which run in virtual servers. The agent retrieves custom-made security settings for a target application by investigating its specific setup, it tests and transparently changes settings via introspection techniques unbeknownst from the perspective of the virtual server. During setting selection, the application's operation is not disturbed nor any user interaction is needed. Since optimal settings can change over time or they can change depending on different tasks the application handles, the agent can continuously adapt settings as well as improve them periodically. We call this approach hot-hardening and present results of an implementation that can hot-harden popular networking applications such as Apache2 and OpenSSH."	2014	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:08	6–15						Hot-hardening	ACSAC '14				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library																																																					
EKF3GIQB	conferencePaper	2014	"Oliveira, Daniela; Navarro, Jesus; Wetzel, Nicholas; Bucci, Max"	Ianus: Secure and Holistic Coexistence with Kernel Extensions - a Immune System-inspired Approach	Proceedings of the 29th Annual ACM Symposium on Applied Computing	978-1-4503-2469-4		10.1145/2554850.2554923	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2554850.2554923	"Kernel extensions, especially device drivers, make up a large fraction of modern OS kernels (approximately 70% in Linux). Most extensions are benign and represent a convenient approach for extending the kernel functionality and allowing a system to communicate with an increasing number of I/O devices. A small fraction of them are malicious and, as they run in kernel space, pose a threat to kernel integrity. From a security viewpoint this situation is paradoxical: modern OSes depend and must co-live with untrustworthy but needed extensions. Our immune system faces the same challenge: our body is made of a large number of bacteria, which are mostly benign and also carry out critical functions for our physiology. However, a small fraction of them pose a threat to our body as they can cause pathologies. The immune system maintains an homeostatic relationship with its microbiota by minimizing contact between bacteria and cell surfaces and confining bacteria to certain sites. Challenging the current trend that advocates leveraging only a hypervisor to defend the kernel (for considering it too vulnerable to defend itself), this paper advocates that modern OSes, like our immune system, should play an active role in maintaining healthy and safe interactions with their extensions. This work presents Ianus, a proof-of-concept prototype for this paradigm using Linux and the Bochs x86 emulator, which successfully minimized kernel extensions interactions with original kernel. Its security was evaluated with real rootkits and benign modules. Ianus' performance was analyzed with system and CPU benchmarks and it caused an small overhead to the system (approximately 12%)."	2014	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:11	1672–1679						Ianus	SAC '14				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library							Collaboration; Immune system; introspection; semantic gap																																														
VXV9NAGM	journalArticle	2006	"Pin Ren; Yan Gao; Zhichun Li; Yan Chen; Watson, B."	IDGraphs: intrusion detection and analysis using stream compositing	IEEE Computer Graphics and Applications		0272-1716	10.1109/MCG.2006.36	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=1607919		Mar-06	8/11/2015 13:01	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:01	28-39		2	26			IDGraphs												CrossRef																																																					
EBRUEWR6	conferencePaper	2013	"Ard, Julie Boxwell; Bishop, Matt; Gates, Carrie; Sun, Michael Xin"	Information Behaving Badly	Proceedings of the 2013 Workshop on New Security Paradigms Workshop	978-1-4503-2582-0		10.1145/2535813.2535825	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2535813.2535825	"Traditionally, insider threat detection has focused on observing human actors -- or, more precisely, computer accounts and processes acting on behalf of those actors -- to model their ""normal"" behavior, then determine if they have performed some anomalous action and, further, if that action is malicious. In this paper, we shift the paradigm from observing human behavior to observing information behavior by modeling how documents flow through an organization. We hypothesize that similar types of documents will exhibit similar workflows, and that a document deviating from its expected workflow indicates potential data leakage."	2013	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:12	107–118							NSPW '13				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library					http://dl.acm.org/ft_gateway.cfm?id=2535825&type=pdf		data exfiltration; data motion; insider threat; workflow																																														
7MNEPNIC	conferencePaper	2009	"Jormakka, Jorma; Lucenius, Jan"	Intruder Detection System Architecture for an SOA-Based C4I2SR System		978-1-4244-5166-1		10.1109/ComputationWorld.2009.73	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=5359600		Nov-09	8/11/2015 13:18	8/12/2015 14:53	8/11/2015 13:18	289-297											IEEE							CrossRef						custom_test_data; true_positve_rate																																															
GZD8NNVW	journalArticle	2014	"Škoberne, Nejc; Maennel, Olaf; Phillips, Iain; Bush, Randy; Zorz, Jan; Ciglaric, Mojca"	IPv4 Address Sharing Mechanism Classification and Tradeoff Analysis	IEEE/ACM Trans. Netw.		1063-6692	10.1109/TNET.2013.2256147	http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TNET.2013.2256147	"The growth of the Internet has made IPv4 addresses a scarce resource. Due to slow IPv6 deployment, IANA-level IPv4 address exhaustion was reached before the world could transition to an IPv6-only Internet. The continuing need for IPv4 reachability will only be supported by IPv4 address sharing. This paper reviews ISP-level address sharing mechanisms, which allow Internet service providers to connect multiple customers who share a single IPv4 address. Some mechanisms come with severe and unpredicted consequences, and all of them come with tradeoffs. We propose a novel classification, which we apply to existing mechanisms such as NAT444 and DS-Lite and proposals such as 4rd, MAP, etc. Our tradeoff analysis reveals insights into many problems including: abuse attribution, performance degradation, address and port usage efficiency, direct intercustomer communication, and availability."	Apr-14	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:00	391–404		2	22															ACM Digital Library					http://dl.acm.org/ft_gateway.cfm?id=2633053&type=pdf		address family translation; address plus port (A+P); carrier grade NAT (CGN); IPv4 address sharing; IPv6 transition; network address translation (NAT)																																														
AKX5GKR7	conferencePaper	2008	"Mrdovic, Sasa; Perunicic, Branislava"	Kerckhoffs' principle for intrusion detection		978-963-8111-68-5		10.1109/NETWKS.2008.4763730	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4763730		Sep-08	8/11/2015 12:57	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 12:57	14-Jan											IEEE							CrossRef						false_positive_rate; true_positive_rate																																															
5AGJCGR8	conferencePaper	2008	"Choi, Y.-H.; Jung, M.-Y.; Seo, S.-W."	L+1-MWM: A Fast Pattern Matching Algorithm for High-Speed Packet Filtering		978-1-4244-2026-1 978-1-4244-2025-4		10.1109/INFOCOM.2008.297	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4509892		Apr-08	8/11/2015 13:17	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:17	2288-2296						L+1-MWM					IEEE							CrossRef						ptn_mtch_time																																															
BAVDWHDD	conferencePaper	2011	"Yu, Junfeng; Zhang, Shengzhi; Liu, Peng; Li, ZhiTang"	LeakProber: A Framework for Profiling Sensitive Data Leakage Paths	Proceedings of the First ACM Conference on Data and Application Security and Privacy	978-1-4503-0466-5		10.1145/1943513.1943525	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1943513.1943525	"In this paper, we present the design, implementation, and evaluation of LeakProber, a framework that leverages the whole system dynamic instrumentation and the inter-procedural analysis to enable data propagation path profiling in production system. We integrate both the static analysis and runtime tracking to establish a holistic and practical approach to generating the sensitive data propagation graph (sDPG) with minimum runtime overhead. We evaluate our system on several data stealing attacks scenario for generating sDPG. The sDPG generated by our system captures multiple aspects of data accessing patterns and provides clear insights into the data leakage path. We also measure the performance of our system and find that it degrades the production system about 6% in the trace-on mode. When our prototype works in the trace-off mode, the runtime overhead is even lower, on an average of 1.5% across each benchmark we run. We believe that it is feasible to directly apply our prototype into production system environment."	2011	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:06	75–84						LeakProber	CODASPY '11				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library					http://dl.acm.org/ft_gateway.cfm?id=1943525&type=pdf		data flow analysis; data leakage; dynamic instrumentation																																														
GUN4WZXA	conferencePaper	2009	"Phung, Phu H.; Sands, David; Chudnov, Andrey"	Lightweight Self-protecting JavaScript	"Proceedings of the 4th International Symposium on Information, Computer, and Communications Security"	978-1-60558-394-5		10.1145/1533057.1533067	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1533057.1533067	"This paper introduces a method to control JavaScript execution. The aim is to prevent or modify inappropriate behaviour caused by e.g. malicious injected scripts or poorly designed third-party code. The approach is based on modifying the code so as to make it self-protecting: the protection mechanism (security policy) is embedded into the code itself and intercepts security relevant API calls. The challenges come from the nature of the JavaScript language: any variables in the scope of the program can be redefined, and code can be created and run on-the-fly. This creates potential problems, respectively, for tamper-proofing the protection mechanism, and for ensuring that no security relevant events bypass the protection. Unlike previous approaches to instrument and monitor JavaScript to enforce or adjust behaviour, the solution we propose is lightweight in that (i) it does not require a modified browser, and (ii) it does not require any run-time parsing and transformation of code (including dynamically generated code). As a result, the method has low run-time overhead compared to other methods satisfying (i), and the lack of need for browser modifications means that the policy can even be applied on the server to mitigate some effects of cross-site scripting bugs."	2009	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:08	47–60							ASIACCS '09				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library					http://dl.acm.org/ft_gateway.cfm?id=1533067&type=pdf		inlined reference monitors; javascript; language based security; Programming																																														
H7XIA2IB	conferencePaper	2014	"Soulé, Robert; Basu, Shrutarshi; Marandi, Parisa Jalili; Pedone, Fernando; Kleinberg, Robert; Sirer, Emin Gun; Foster, Nate"	Merlin: A Language for Provisioning Network Resources	Proceedings of the 10th ACM International on Conference on Emerging Networking Experiments and Technologies	978-1-4503-3279-8		10.1145/2674005.2674989	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2674005.2674989	"This paper presents Merlin, a new framework for managing resources in software-defined networks. With Merlin, administrators express high-level policies using programs in a declarative language. The language includes logical predicates to identify sets of packets, regular expressions to encode forwarding paths, and arithmetic formulas to specify bandwidth constraints. The Merlin compiler maps these policies into a constraint problem that determines bandwidth allocations using parameterizable heuristics. It then generates code that can be executed on the network elements to enforce the policies. To allow network tenants to dynamically adapt policies to their needs, Merlin provides mechanisms for delegating control of sub-policies and for verifying that modifications made to sub-policies do not violate global constraints. Experiments demonstrate the expressiveness and effectiveness of Merlin on real-world topologies and applications. Overall, Merlin simplifies network administration by providing high-level abstractions for specifying network policies that provision network resources."	2014	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:58	213–226						Merlin	CoNEXT '14				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library					http://dl.acm.org/ft_gateway.cfm?id=2674989&type=pdf		delegation; merlin; Resource management; software-defined networking; verification																																														
CQ8BWIMQ	conferencePaper	2011	"Cipriani, Nazario; Schiller, Oliver; Mitschang, Bernhard"	M-TOP: Multi-target Operator Placement of Query Graphs for Data Streams	Proceedings of the 15th Symposium on International Database Engineering & Applications	978-1-4503-0627-0		10.1145/2076623.2076631	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2076623.2076631	"Nowadays, many applications processes stream-based data, such as financial market analysis, network intrusion detection, or visualization applications. To process stream-based data in an application-independent manner, distributed stream processing systems emerged. They typically translate a query to an operator graph, place the operators to stream processing nodes, and execute them to process the streamed data. The operator placement is crucial in such systems, as it deeply influences query execution. Often, different stream-based applications require dedicated placement of query graphs according to their specific objectives, e.g. bandwidth not less than 500 MBit/s and costs not more that 1 cost unit. This fact constraints operator placement. Existing approaches do not take into account application-specific objectives, thus not reflecting application-specific placement decisions. As objectives might conflict among each other, operator placement is subject to delicate trade-offs, such as bandwidth maximization is more important than cost reduction. Thus, the challenge is to find a solution which considers the application-specific objectives and their trade-offs. We present M-TOP, an QoS-aware multi-target operator placement framework for data stream systems. Particularly, we propose an operator placement strategy considering application-specific targets consisting of objectives, their respective trade-offs specifications, bottleneck conditions, and ranking schemes to compute a suitable placement. We integrated M-TOP into NexusDS, our distributed data stream processing middleware, and provide an experimental evaluation to show the effectiveness of M-TOP."	2011	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:16	52–60						M-TOP	IDEAS '11				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library					http://dl.acm.org/ft_gateway.cfm?id=2076631&type=pdf																																																
7AF653CS	conferencePaper	2011	"Masiero, Andrey A.; Leite, Mayara G.; Filgueiras, Lucia Vilela Leite; Aquino, Plinio Thomaz, Jr."	Multidirectional Knowledge Extraction Process for Creating Behavioral Personas	Proceedings of the 10th Brazilian Symposium on on Human Factors in Computing Systems and the 5th Latin American Conference on Human-Computer Interaction	978-85-7669-257-7			http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2254436.2254454	"The consideration of user aspects in the design of computer systems is vital to maintaining the quality of these products. The search for user information as to their interests, needs, and behaviors, requires actions that can be costly. However, the use of such information in an inefficient, inaccurate manner, without the formation of knowledge discourages the process of user-centered development. Interface designers need to collect information and consume it efficiently. One option for documenting and efficiently consuming the information from user research is to apply the technique of personas. The extraction of knowledge in databases is the selection and processing of data with the purpose of identifying new patterns, provide greater accuracy on known patterns, and model the real world. Thus, this work presents a multidirectional process of extracting knowledge for creating behavioral personas. The processes of data mining are performed and compared with variations allowing a real knowledge extraction in the creation of personas. The process is multidirectional being able to be applied in both directions for the composition of any kind of personas. The results of the work demonstrate the extraction of knowledge originating from demographic information to the construction of personas focusing on behavioral aspects."	2011	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:01	91–99							IHC+CLIHC '11				Brazilian Computer Society	"Porto Alegre, Brazil, Brazil"						ACM Digital Library					http://dl.acm.org/ft_gateway.cfm?id=2254454&type=pdf		behavioral personas; data mining; Knowledge extraction; user modeling; user profile																																														
3R3QQBWV	conferencePaper	2013	"Wang, Wei; Li, Baochun; Liang, Ben"	Multi-Resource Round Robin: A low complexity packet scheduler with Dominant Resource Fairness		978-1-4799-1270-4		10.1109/ICNP.2013.6733610	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6733610		Oct-13	8/11/2015 13:11	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:11	10-Jan						Multi-Resource Round Robin					IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
TI9TND6C	conferencePaper	2010	"Meyerovich, Leo A.; Felt, Adrienne Porter; Miller, Mark S."	Object Views: Fine-grained Sharing in Browsers	Proceedings of the 19th International Conference on World Wide Web	978-1-60558-799-8		10.1145/1772690.1772764	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1772690.1772764	"Browsers do not currently support the secure sharing of JavaScript objects between principals. We present this problem as the need for object views, which are consistent and controllable versions of objects. Multiple views can be made for the same object and customized for the recipients. We implement object views with a JavaScript library that wraps shared objects and interposes on all access attempts. The security challenge is to fully mediate access to objects shared through a view and prevent privilege escalation. We discuss how object views can be deployed in two settings: same-origin sharing with rewriting-based JavaScript isolation systems like Google Caja, and inter-origin sharing between browser frames over a message-passing channel. To facilitate simple document sharing, we build a policy system for declaratively defining policies for document object views. Notably, our document policy system makes it possible to hide elements without breaking document structure invariants. Developers can control the fine-grained behavior of object views with an aspect system that accepts programmatic policies."	2010	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:08	721–730						Object Views	WWW '10				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library					http://dl.acm.org/ft_gateway.cfm?id=1772764&type=pdf		aspect; browser; ecmascript; javascript; membrane; reference monitor; remote object; same origin policy; web security; wrapper																																														
54E8WG4X	conferencePaper	2009	"Nechaev, Boris; Paxson, Vern; Allman, Mark; Gurtov, Andrei"	On Calibrating Enterprise Switch Measurements	Proceedings of the 9th ACM SIGCOMM Conference on Internet Measurement Conference	978-1-60558-771-4		10.1145/1644893.1644910	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1644893.1644910	"The complexity of modern enterprise networks is ever-increasing, and our understanding of these important networks is not keeping pace. Our insight into intra-subnet traffic (staying within a single LAN) is particularly limited, due to the widespread use of Ethernet switches that preclude ready LAN-wide monitoring. We have recently undertaken an approach to obtaining extensive intra-subnet visibility based on tapping sets of Ethernet switch ports simultaneously. However, doing so leads to a number of measurement calibration issues that require careful consideration to address. First, one must correctly account for redundant copies of packets that appear due to switch flooding, which if not accurately identified can greatly skew subsequent analysis results. We show that a simple, natural rule one might use for doing so in fact introduces systematic errors, but an altered version of the rule performs significantly better. We then employ this revised rule to aid with calibration issues concerning the fidelity of packet timestamps and the amount of measurement loss that our collection apparatus incurred. Additionally, we develop techniques to ""map"" the monitored network in terms of identifying key topological components, such as subnet boundaries, which hosts were directly monitored, and the presence of ""hidden"" switches and hubs. Finally, we present initial analyses demonstrating that the magnitude and diversity of traffic at the subnet level is in fact striking, highlighting the importance of obtaining and correctly calibrating switch-level enterprise traces."	2009	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:12	143–155							IMC '09				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library					http://dl.acm.org/ft_gateway.cfm?id=1644910&type=pdf		enterprise networks; network traces; switch-based packet capture; trace calibration																																														
EBX2EVC8	conferencePaper	2009	"Zhang, Ruishan; Wang, Xinyuan; Farley, Ryan; Yang, Xiaohui; Jiang, Xuxian"	On the Feasibility of Launching the Man-in-the-middle Attacks on VoIP from Remote Attackers	"Proceedings of the 4th International Symposium on Information, Computer, and Communications Security"	978-1-60558-394-5		10.1145/1533057.1533069	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1533057.1533069	"The man-in-the-middle (MITM) attack has been shown to be one of the most serious threats to the security and trust of existing VoIP protocols and systems. For example, the MITM who is in the VoIP signaling and/or media path can easily wiretap, divert and even hijack selected VoIP calls by tempering with the VoIP signaling and/or media traffic. Since all previously identified MITM attacks on VoIP require the adversary initially in the VoIP signaling and/or media path, there is a common belief that it is infeasible for a remote attacker, who is not initially in the VoIP path, to launch any MITM attack on VoIP. This makes people think that securing all the nodes along the normal path of VoIP traffic is sufficient to prevent MITM attacks on VoIP. In this paper, we demonstrate that a remote attacker who is not initially in the path of VoIP traffic can indeed launch all kinds of MITM attacks on VoIP by exploiting DNS and VoIP implementation vulnerabilities. Our case study of Vonage VoIP, the No. 1 residential VoIP service in the U.S. market, shows that a remote attacker from anywhere on the Internet can stealthily become a remote MITM through DNS spoofing attack on a Vonage phone, as long as the remote attacker knows the phone number and the IP address of the Vonage phone. We further show that the remote attacker can effectively wiretap and hijack targeted Vonage VoIP calls after becoming the remote MITM. Our results demonstrate that (1) the MITM attack on VoIP is much more realistic than previously thought; (2) securing all nodes along the path of VoIP traffic is not adequate to prevent MITM attack on VoIP; (3) vulnerabilities of non-VoIP-specific protocols (e.g., DNS) can indeed lead to compromise of VoIP."	2009	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:09	61–69							ASIACCS '09				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library					http://dl.acm.org/ft_gateway.cfm?id=1533069&type=pdf		DNS spoofing; MITM attacks; SIP; VoIP security																																														
JCGSXDV8	conferencePaper	2006	"Sourdis, Ioannis; Dimopoulos, Vasilis; Pnevmatikatos, Dionisios; Vassiliadis, Stamatis"	Packet pre-filtering for network intrusion detection	"Architecture for Networking and Communications systems, 2006. ANCS 2006. ACM/IEEE Symposium on"	1-59593-580-0					2006	8/11/2015 13:10	8/11/2015 13:55		183-192											IEEE																																																												
