Zotero Export	11/6/2015	(Tagged papers)	Zotero/IEEE																																																																																			
Key	Item Type	Publication Year	Author	Title	Publication Title	ISBN	ISSN	DOI	Url	Abstract Note	Date	Date Added	Date Modified	Access Date	Pages	Num Pages	Issue	Volume	Number Of Volumes	Journal Abbreviation	Short Title	Series	Series Number	Series Text	Series Title	Publisher	Place	Language	Rights	Type	Archive	Archive Location	Library Catalog	Call Number	Extra	Notes	File Attachments	Link Attachments	Manual Tags	Automatic Tags	Editor	Series Editor	Translator	Contributor	Attorney Agent	Book Author	Cast Member	Commenter	Composer	Cosponsor	Counsel	Interviewer	Producer	Recipient	Reviewed Author	Scriptwriter	Words By	Guest	Number	Edition	Running Time	Scale	Medium	Artwork Size	Filing Date	Application Number	Assignee	Issuing Authority	Country	Meeting Name	Conference Name	Court	References	Reporter	Legal Status	Priority Numbers	Programming Language	Version	System	Code	Code Number	Section	Session	Committee	History	Legislative Body
GUCXPPMD	conferencePaper	2009	"Pungila, Ciprian-Petrisor"	A Bray-Curtis Weighted Automaton for Detecting Malicious Code Through System-Call Analysis		978-1-4244-5910-0		10.1109/SYNASC.2009.41	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=5460823		Sep-09	8/11/2015 13:12	8/11/2015 14:06	8/11/2015 13:12	392-400											IEEE							CrossRef						memory_usage; scanning_time; syscalls_per_time																																															
N6PF9AUB	conferencePaper	2012	"Poston, Howard E."	A brief taxonomy of intrusion detection strategies		978-1-4673-2792-3 978-1-4673-2791-6 978-1-4673-2790-9		10.1109/NAECON.2012.6531064	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6531064		Jul-12	8/11/2015 13:12	9/2/2015 18:36	8/11/2015 13:12	255-263											IEEE							CrossRef						lit_review																																															
CHBTRC2D	conferencePaper	2011	"Chen, Xinming; Ge, Kailin; Chen, Zhen; Li, Jun"	AC-Suffix-Tree: Buffer Free String Matching on Out-of-Sequence Packets		978-1-4577-1454-2		10.1109/ANCS.2011.14	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6062710		Oct-11	8/11/2015 13:18	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:18	36-44						AC-Suffix-Tree					IEEE							CrossRef						custom_test_data; memory_usage; num_states; throughput																																															
SJHJ87IC	conferencePaper	2008	"Makanju, Adetokunbo; Zincir-Heywood, Nur; Milios, Evangelos"	Adaptabilty of a GP Based IDS on Wireless Networks		978-0-7695-3102-1		10.1109/ARES.2008.50	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4529352		Mar-08	8/11/2015 13:12	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:12	310-318											IEEE							CrossRef						false_postive_rate; recall																																															
VU5U37RI	conferencePaper	1999	"Lee, Wenke; Stolfo, S.J.; Mok, K.W."	A data mining framework for building intrusion detection models	"Proceedings of the 1999 IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy, 1999"			10.1109/SECPRI.1999.766909		"There is often the need to update an installed intrusion detection system (IDS) due to new attack methods or upgraded computing environments. Since many current IDSs are constructed by manual encoding of expert knowledge, changes to IDSs are expensive and slow. We describe a data mining framework for adaptively building Intrusion Detection (ID) models. The central idea is to utilize auditing programs to extract an extensive set of features that describe each network connection or host session, and apply data mining programs to learn rules that accurately capture the behavior of intrusions and normal activities. These rules can then be used for misuse detection and anomaly detection. New detection models are incorporated into an existing IDS through a meta-learning (or co-operative learning) process, which produces a meta detection model that combines evidence from multiple models. We discuss the strengths of our data mining programs, namely, classification, meta-learning, association rules, and frequent episodes. We report on the results of applying these programs to the extensively gathered network audit data for the 1998 DARPA Intrusion Detection Evaluation Program"	1999	7/24/2014 17:08	7/24/2014 17:08		120-132																		IEEE Xplore				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\23FU4ETI\abs_all.html; C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\4WR9P2XR\Lee et al. - 1999 - A data mining framework for building intrusion det.pdf		DarpaIDE; false_positive_rate; num_features; true_positive_rate	1998 DARPA Intrusion Detection Evaluation Program; anomaly detection; association rules; auditing; auditing programs; authorisation; Buildings; computer network management; Computer networks; Computer science; co-operative learning; data mining framework; Data security; Encoding; expert knowledge; Expert systems; frequent episodes; Gas detectors; host session; Identity-based encryption; IDS update; intrusion detection models; learning (artificial intelligence); manual encoding; meta detection model; meta-learning; misuse detection; multiple models; network connection; Protection; upgraded computing environments																															"Proceedings of the 1999 IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy, 1999"															
KE2AAD8P	conferencePaper	2006	"Kumar, Sailesh; Turner, Jonathan; Williams, John"	Advanced Algorithms for Fast and Scalable Deep Packet Inspection	Proceedings of the 2006 ACM/IEEE Symposium on Architecture for Networking and Communications Systems	978-1-59593-580-9		10.1145/1185347.1185359	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1185347.1185359	"Modern deep packet inspection systems use regular expressions to define various patterns of interest in network data streams. Deterministic Finite Automata (DFA) are commonly used to parse regular expressions. DFAs are fast, but can require prohibitively large amounts of memory for patterns arising in network applications. Traditional DFA table compression only slightly reduces the memory required and requires an additional memory access per input character. Alternative representations of regular expressions, such as NFAs and Delayed Input DFAs (D2FA) require less memory but sacrifice throughput. In this paper we introduce the Content Addressed Delayed Input DFA (CD2FA), which provides a compact representation of regular expressions that match the throughput of traditional uncompressed DFAs. A CD2FA addresses successive states of a D2FA using their content, rather than a ""content-less"" identifier. This makes selected information available earlier in the state traversal process, which makes it possible to avoid unnecessary memory accesses. We demonstrate that such content-addressing can be effectively used to obtain automata that are very compact and can achieve high throughput. Specifically, we show that for an application using thousands of patterns defined by regular expressions, CD2FAs use as little as 10% of the space required by a conventional compressed DFA, and match the throughput of an uncompressed DFA."	2006	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:01	81–92							ANCS '06				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library						Cisco_regex; memory_usage; num_states; num_transitions	deep packet inspection; DFA; regular expressions																																														
PDPV84M6	journalArticle	2010	"Bartoli, Alberto; Davanzo, Giorgio; Medvet, Eric"	A Framework for Large-Scale Detection of Web Site Defacements	ACM Trans. Internet Technol.		1533-5399	10.1145/1852096.1852098	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1852096.1852098	"Web site defacement, the process of introducing unauthorized modifications to a Web site, is a very common form of attack. In this paper we describe and evaluate experimentally a framework that may constitute the basis for a defacement detection service capable of monitoring thousands of remote Web sites systematically and automatically. In our framework an organization may join the service by simply providing the URLs of the resources to be monitored along with the contact point of an administrator. The monitored organization may thus take advantage of the service with just a few mouse clicks, without installing any software locally or changing its own daily operational processes. Our approach is based on anomaly detection and allows monitoring the integrity of many remote Web resources automatically while remaining fully decoupled from them, in particular, without requiring any prior knowledge about those resources. We evaluated our approach over a selection of dynamic resources and a set of publicly available defacements. The results are very satisfactory: all attacks are detected while keeping false positives to a minimum. We also assessed performance and scalability of our proposal and we found that it may indeed constitute the basis for actually deploying the proposed service on a large scale."	Oct-10	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:59	10:1–10:37		3	10															ACM Digital Library						custom_test_data; false_negative_rate; false_positive_rate; max_resources	experimental evaluation; intrusion detection; monitoring service; Web site defacement																																														
FZ3S63UD	conferencePaper	2008	"Fries, Terrence P."	A Fuzzy-genetic Approach to Network Intrusion Detection	Proceedings of the 10th Annual Conference Companion on Genetic and Evolutionary Computation	978-1-60558-131-6		10.1145/1388969.1389037	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1388969.1389037	"Computer networks have expanded significantly in use and numbers. This expansion makes them more vulnerable to attack by unwanted agents. Many current intrusion detection systems (IDS) are unable to identify unknown or mutated attack modes or are unable to operate in a dynamic environment as is necessary with mobile networks. As a result, it is necessary to find new ways to implement and operate intrusion detection systems. Genetic-based systems offer to ability to adapt to changing environments, robustness to noise and the ability to identify unknown attack methods. This paper presents a fuzzy-genetic approach to intrusion detection that is shown to increase the performance of an IDS."	2008	7/28/2014 22:07	7/28/2014 22:07	7/28/2014 22:07	2141–2146							GECCO '08				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\PMW5AKGH\Fries - 2008 - A Fuzzy-genetic Approach to Network Intrusion Dete.pdf		false_positive_rate; KDD99; num_features; true_positive_rate	fuzzy sets; genetic algorithms; intrusion detection; security																																														
HQQX3F7H	conferencePaper	2006	"Diaz-gomez, Pedro; Hougen, Dean"	A Genetic Algorithm Approach for Doing Misuse Detection in Audit Trail Files		978-0-7695-2708-6		10.1109/CIC.2006.6	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4023829		Nov-06	8/11/2015 13:08	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:08	329-338											IEEE							CrossRef						num_generations																																															
RCI4SPSK	journalArticle	2013	"Jiang, F.; Daoyi Dong; Longbing Cao; Frater, M. R."	Agent-Based Self-Adaptable Context-Aware Network Vulnerability Assessment	IEEE Transactions on Network and Service Management		1932-4537	10.1109/TNSM.2013.090313.120388	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6599023		Sep-13	8/11/2015 12:53	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 12:53	255-270		3	10															CrossRef						computational_time; false_postive_rate; recall																																															
ZEUBX48N	conferencePaper	2006	"Kumar, Sailesh; Dharmapurikar, Sarang; Yu, Fang; Crowley, Patrick; Turner, Jonathan"	Algorithms to Accelerate Multiple Regular Expressions Matching for Deep Packet Inspection	"Proceedings of the 2006 Conference on Applications, Technologies, Architectures, and Protocols for Computer Communications"	978-1-59593-308-9		10.1145/1159913.1159952	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1159913.1159952	"There is a growing demand for network devices capable of examining the content of data packets in order to improve network security and provide application-specific services. Most high performance systems that perform deep packet inspection implement simple string matching algorithms to match packets against a large, but finite set of strings. owever, there is growing interest in the use of regular expression-based pattern matching, since regular expressions offer superior expressive power and flexibility. Deterministic finite automata (DFA) representations are typically used to implement regular expressions. However, DFA representations of regular expression sets arising in network applications require large amounts of memory, limiting their practical application.In this paper, we introduce a new representation for regular expressions, called the Delayed Input DFA (D2FA), which substantially reduces space equirements as compared to a DFA. A D2FA is constructed by transforming a DFA via incrementally replacing several transitions of the automaton with a single default transition. Our approach dramatically reduces the number of distinct transitions between states. For a collection of regular expressions drawn from current commercial and academic systems, a D2FA representation reduces transitions by more than 95%. Given the substantially reduced space equirements, we describe an efficient architecture that can perform deep packet inspection at multi-gigabit rates. Our architecture uses multiple on-chip memories in such a way that each remains uniformly occupied and accessed over a short duration, thus effectively distributing the load and enabling high throughput. Our architecture can provide ostffective packet content scanning at OC-192 rates with memory requirements that are consistent with current ASIC technology."	2006	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:09	339–350							SIGCOMM '06				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library						Cisco_regex; default_length; num_distinct_transitions; num_duplicate_transitions; num_states; num_transitions	deep packet inspection; DFA; regular expressions																																														
BG2HRSBU	conferencePaper	2015	"Owezarski, Philippe"	A Near Real-Time Algorithm for Autonomous Identification and Characterization of Honeypot Attacks	"Proceedings of the 10th ACM Symposium on Information, Computer and Communications Security"	978-1-4503-3245-3		10.1145/2714576.2714580	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2714576.2714580	"Monitoring communication networks and their traffic is of essential importance for estimating the risk in the Internet, and therefore designing suited protection systems for computer networks. Network and traffic analysis can be done thanks to measurement devices or honeypots. However, analyzing the huge amount of gathered data, and characterizing the anomalies and attacks contained in these traces remain complex and time consuming tasks, done by network and security experts using poorly automatized tools, and are consequently slow and costly. In this paper, we present an unsupervised algorithm - called UNADA for Unsupervised Network Anomaly Detection Algorithm - for identification and characterization of security related anomalies and attacks occurring in honeypots. This automatized method does not need any attack signature database, learning phase, or labeled traffic. This corresponds to a major step towards autonomous security systems. This paper also shows how it is possible from anomalies characterization results to infer filtering rules that could serve for automatically configuring network routers, switches or firewalls. The performances of UNADA in terms of attacks identification accuracy are evaluated using honeypot traffic traces gathered on the honeypot network of the University of Maryland. The time latency for producing such accurate results are also presented, especially showing how the parallelization capabilities of the algorithm help reducing this latency."	2015	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:56	531–542							ASIA CCS '15				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library						computational_time; custom_test_data; false_positive_rate; true_positive_rate	anomaly characterization; autonomous security systems; big traffic data; honeypot attack identification; unsupervised machine learning																																														
M75PS3MF	conferencePaper	2009	"Akujobi, Frank; Lambadaris, Ioannis; Kranakis, Evangelos"	An Integrated Approach to Detection of Fast and Slow Scanning Worms	"Proceedings of the 4th International Symposium on Information, Computer, and Communications Security"	978-1-60558-394-5		10.1145/1533057.1533071	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1533057.1533071	"The propagation speed of fast scanning worms and the stealthy nature of slow scanning worms present unique challenges to intrusion detection. Typically, techniques optimized for detection of fast scanning worms fail to detect slow scanning worms, and vice versa. In practice, there is interest in developing an integrated approach to detecting both classes of worms. In this paper, we propose and analyze a unique integrated detection approach capable of detecting and identifying traffic flow(s) responsible for simultaneous fast and slow scanning malicious worm attacks. The approach uses a combination of evidence from distributed host-based anomaly detectors, a self-adapting profiler and Bayesian inference from network heuristics to detect intrusion activity due to both fast and slow scanning worms. We assume that the extreme nature of fast scanning worm epidemics make them well suited for extreme value theory and use sample mean excess function to determine appropriate thresholds for detection of such worms. Random scanning worm behavior is considered in analyzing the stochastic time intervals that affect behavior of the detection technique. Based on the analysis, a probability model for worm detection interval using the detection scheme was developed. Simulations are used to validate our assumptions and analysis."	2009	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:06	80–91							ASIACCS '09				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library						rep_lat; scan_rate	anomaly detection; Bayesian inference; detection interval; intrusion detection; probability model; worms																																														
Z47FSQFR	journalArticle	1993	"Lunt, Teresa F."	A survey of intrusion detection techniques	Computers & Security		0167-4048	10.1016/0167-4048(93)90029-5	http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0167404893900295	"Today's computer systems are vulnerable both to abuse by insiders and to penetration by outsiders, as evidenced by the growing number of incidents reported in the press. To close all security loopholes from today's systems is infeasible, and no combination of technologies can prevent legitimate users from abusing their authority in a system; thus auditing is viewed as the last line of defense. Over the past several years, the computer security community has been developing automated tools to analyze computer system audit data for suspicious user behavior. This paper describes the use of such tools for detecting computer system intrusion and describes further technologies that may be of use for intrusion detection in the future."	Jun-93	7/24/2014 17:11	7/24/2014 17:11	7/24/2014 17:11	405-418		4	12		Computers & Security													ScienceDirect				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\T4KMBB8J\Lunt - 1993 - A survey of intrusion detection techniques.pdf; C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\BVQZ8QS6\0167404893900295.html		lit_review																																															
8SB5XA5P	conferencePaper	2011	"Szabó, Géza; Turányi, Zoltán; Toka, László; Molnár, Sándor; Santos, Alysson"	Automatic Protocol Signature Generation Framework for Deep Packet Inspection	Proceedings of the 5th International ICST Conference on Performance Evaluation Methodologies and Tools	978-1-936968-09-1			http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2151688.2151721	"We present an automatic application protocol signature generating framework for Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) techniques with performance evaluation. We propose to utilize algorithms from the field of bioinformatics. We also present preprocessing methods to accelerate our system. Moreover, we developed several postprocessing techniques to refine the accuracy of the results. Finally, we propose a DPI system, based on approximate string matching, and find it a viable, novel alternative for the refinement of exact string matching algorithm's results."	2011	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:08	291–299							VALUETOOLS '11				"ICST (Institute for Computer Sciences, Social-Informatics and Telecommunications Engineering)"	"ICST, Brussels, Belgium, Belgium"						ACM Digital Library						computational_time; coverage_flow; custom_test_data	automatic protocol signature generation; deep packet inspection; motif finding																																														
RRE7WFVR	conferencePaper	2010	"Goodstein, Michelle L.; Vlachos, Evangelos; Chen, Shimin; Gibbons, Phillip B.; Kozuch, Michael A.; Mowry, Todd C."	Butterfly Analysis: Adapting Dataflow Analysis to Dynamic Parallel Monitoring	Proceedings of the Fifteenth Edition of ASPLOS on Architectural Support for Programming Languages and Operating Systems	978-1-60558-839-1		10.1145/1736020.1736050	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1736020.1736050	"Online program monitoring is an effective technique for detecting bugs and security attacks in running applications. Extending these tools to monitor parallel programs is challenging because the tools must account for inter-thread dependences and relaxed memory consistency models. Existing tools assume sequential consistency and often slow down the monitored program by orders of magnitude. In this paper, we present a novel approach that avoids these pitfalls by not relying on strong consistency models or detailed inter-thread dependence tracking. Instead, we only assume that events in the distant past on all threads have become visible; we make no assumptions on (and avoid the overheads of tracking) the relative ordering of more recent events on other threads. To overcome the potential state explosion of considering all the possible orderings among recent events, we adapt two techniques from static dataflow analysis, reaching definitions and reaching expressions, to this new domain of dynamic parallel monitoring. Significant modifications to these techniques are proposed to ensure the correctness and efficiency of our approach. We show how our adapted analysis can be used in two popular memory and security tools. We prove that our approach does not miss errors, and sacrifices precision only due to the lack of a relative ordering among recent events. Moreover, our simulation study on a collection of Splash-2 and Parsec 2.0 benchmarks running a memory-checking tool on a hardware-assisted logging platform demonstrates the potential benefits in trading off a very low false positive rate for (i) reduced overhead and (ii) the ability to run on relaxed consistency models."	2010	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:08	257–270						Butterfly Analysis	ASPLOS XV				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library						computational_time; custom_test_data; precision	data flow analysis; dynamic program monitoring; parallel programming; static analysis																																														
U7577H53	conferencePaper	2013	"Ali, Muhammad Qasim; Al-Shaer, Ehab"	Configuration-based IDS for Advanced Metering Infrastructure	Proceedings of the 2013 ACM SIGSAC Conference on Computer & Communications Security	978-1-4503-2477-9		10.1145/2508859.2516745	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2508859.2516745	"Smart grid deployment initiatives have been witnessed in the past recent years. Smart grids provide bi-directional communication between meters and headend system through Advanced Metering Infrastructure (AMI). Recent studies highlight the threats targeting AMI. Despite the need of tailored Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS) for the smart grid, very limited progress has been made in this area. Unlike traditional networks, smart grid has its own unique challenges, such as limited computational power devices and potentially high deployment cost, that restrict the deployment options of intrusion detectors. We show that smart grid exhibits deterministic and predictable behavior that can be accurately modeled to develop intrusion detection system. In this paper, we show that AMI behavior can be modeled using event logs collected at smart collectors, which in turn can be verified using the specifications invariant generated from the configurations of the AMI devices. Event logs are modeled using fourth order Markov Chain and specifications are written in Linear Temporal Logic (LTL). The approach provides robustness against evasion and mimicry attacks, however, we discuss that it still can be evaded to a certain extent. We validate our approach on a real-world dataset of thousands of meters collected at the AMI of a leading utility provider."	2013	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:08	451–462							CCS '13				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library						accuracy; custom_test_data; precision; recall	advanced metering infrastructure; intrusion detection systems; smart grid																																														
3QEZ8BWB	conferencePaper	2012	"Jafer, Shafagh; Jafer, Yasser; Wainer, Gabriel"	Data Mining with Cellular Discrete Event Modeling and Simulation	Proceedings of the 45th Annual Simulation Symposium	978-1-61839-784-3			http://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=2331751.2331755	"Data mining is the process of extracting patterns from data. A main step in this process is referred to as data classification. In this work, we investigate the use of the Cell-DEVS formalism for classifying data. The cells in a Cell-DEVS based grid are individually very simple but together they can represent complex behavior and are capable of self-organization. Three classifier models are implemented using Cell-DEVS. Different simulation scenarios are presented investigating the effect of Von Neumann versus Moore neighborhood in the classifiers' models. We show that effective classification performance, comparable to those produced by complex data mining techniques, can be obtained from the collective behavior of discrete-event cellular grids."	2012	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:51	4:1–4:8							ANSS '12				Society for Computer Simulation International	"San Diego, CA, USA"						ACM Digital Library							Cell-DEVS; cellular discrete event simulation; classification; data mining																																														
7TUGN6F3	conferencePaper	2005	"da Silva, Ana Paula R.; Martins, Marcelo H. T.; Rocha, Bruno P. S.; Loureiro, Antonio A. F.; Ruiz, Linnyer B.; Wong, Hao Chi"	Decentralized Intrusion Detection in Wireless Sensor Networks	Proceedings of the 1st ACM International Workshop on Quality of Service &Amp; Security in Wireless and Mobile Networks	1-59593-241-0		10.1145/1089761.1089765	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1089761.1089765	"Wireless sensor networks (WSNs) have many potential applications. Furthermore, in many scenarios WSNs are of interest to adversaries and they become susceptible to some types of attacks since they are deployed in open and unprotected environments and are constituted of cheap small devices. Preventive mechanisms can be applied to protect WSNs against some types of attacks. However, there are some attacks for which there is no known prevention methods. For these cases, it is necessary to use some mechanism of intrusion detection. Besides preventing the intruder from causing damages to the network, the intrusion detection system (IDS) can acquire information related to the attack techniques, helping in the development of prevention systems. In this work we propose an IDS that fits the demands and restrictions of WSNs. Simulation results reveal that the proposed IDS is efficient and accurate in detecting different kinds of simulated attacks."	2005	7/28/2014 22:52	7/28/2014 22:52	7/28/2014 22:52	16–23							Q2SWinet '05				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\CFIW9NVK\da Silva et al. - 2005 - Decentralized Intrusion Detection in Wireless Sens.pdf		energy_consumption; false_positive_rate; num_nodes; num_rules	intrusion detection; security; wireless sensor networks																																														
9RQQWBPB	conferencePaper	2003	"Vigna, Giovanni; Valeur, Fredrik; Kemmerer, Richard A."	Designing and Implementing a Family of Intrusion Detection Systems	Proceedings of the 9th European Software Engineering Conference Held Jointly with 11th ACM SIGSOFT International Symposium on Foundations of Software Engineering	1-58113-743-5		10.1145/940071.940084	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/940071.940084	"Intrusion detection systems are distributed applications that analyze the events in a networked system to identify malicious behavior. The analysis is performed using a number of attack models (or signatures) that are matched against a specific event stream. Intrusion detection systems may operate in heterogeneous environments, analyzing different types of event streams. Currently, intrusion detection systems and the corresponding attack modeling languages are developed following an ad hoc approach to match the characteristics of specific target environments. As the number of systems that have to be protected increases, this approach results in increased development effort. To overcome this limitation, we developed a framework, called STAT, that supports the development of new intrusion detection functionality in a modular fashion. The STAT framework can be extended following a well-defined process to implement intrusion detection systems tailored to specific environments, platforms, and event streams. The STAT framework is novel in the fact that the extension process also includes the extension of the attack modeling language. The resulting intrusion detection systems represent a software family whose members share common attack modeling features and the ability to reconfigure their behavior dynamically."	2003	7/25/2014 19:29	7/25/2014 19:29	7/25/2014 19:29	88–97							ESEC/FSE-11				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\SNHXGJ5D\Vigna et al. - 2003 - Designing and Implementing a Family of Intrusion D.pdf		loc; MIT_LL	intrusion detection; object-oriented frameworks; program families; security																																														
QQZ7A8GQ	conferencePaper	2007	"Khanna, Rahul; Liu, Huaping"	Distributed and Control Theoretic Approach to Intrusion Detection	Proceedings of the 2007 International Conference on Wireless Communications and Mobile Computing	978-1-59593-695-0		10.1145/1280940.1280965	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1280940.1280965	"Ad hoc wireless networks are more vulnerable to malicious attacks than traditional wired networks due to the silent nature of these attacks and the inability of the conventional intrusion detection systems (IDS) to detect them. These attacks operate under the threshold boundaries during an intrusion attempt and can only be identified by profiling the complete system activity in relation to a normal behavior. In this paper we discuss a control-theoretic Hidden Markov Model (HMM) strategy for intrusion detection using distributed observations across multiple nodes. This model consists of a distributed HMM engine that executes in a randomly selected monitor node and functions as a part of the feedback control engine. This drives the defensive response based on hysteresis to reduce the frequency of false positives, thereby avoiding inappropriate ad hoc responses."	2007	7/28/2014 22:57	7/28/2014 22:57	7/28/2014 22:57	115–120							IWCMC '07				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\W8VD2BWX\Khanna and Liu - 2007 - Distributed and Control Theoretic Approach to Intr.pdf		num_nodes; roc; true_positive_rate	hidden markov models; IDS; intrusion detection; wireless ad-hoc networks																																														
D3RB7AEG	conferencePaper	2013	"do Carmo, Rodrigo; Hollick, Matthias"	DogoIDS: A Mobile and Active Intrusion Detection System for IEEE 802.11s Wireless Mesh Networks	Proceedings of the 2Nd ACM Workshop on Hot Topics on Wireless Network Security and Privacy	978-1-4503-2003-0		10.1145/2463183.2463187	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2463183.2463187	"Wireless Mesh Networks (WMN) are particularly vulnerable to attacks, since they feature constraint nodes, multi-hop communication, and an open wireless communication channel. These features limit the feasibility of the deployment of contemporary Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS): centralized systems fail because there is no strict network boundary, and distributed and/or cooperative systems challenge the limited resources of the nodes. As a result, practical IDSs for WMNs are scarce, and existing systems are limited with respect to detection capabilities. In this paper we present the design, implementation, and evaluation of ""DogoIDS"": an open source, mobile, active-probing-based intrusion detection system. Exploiting mobility allows to mitigate the limitations of distributed, node-dependent systems. The active nature of the system achieves detection capabilities beyond that of a purely passive system. We show the accuracy and speed of our prototype in a testbed WMN---based on the IEEE 802.11s standard---under realistic attacks."	2013	7/28/2014 22:06	7/28/2014 22:06	7/28/2014 22:06	13–18						DogoIDS	HotWiSec '13				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\7W2439XA\do Carmo and Hollick - 2013 - DogoIDS A Mobile and Active Intrusion Detection S.pdf		num_attackers; num_nodes; rep_lat; traffic_increase; true_positive_rate	intrusion detection; security; wireless mesh networks																																														
VMWGVA76	conferencePaper	2012	"Schütt, Kristof; Kloft, Marius; Bikadorov, Alexander; Rieck, Konrad"	Early Detection of Malicious Behavior in JavaScript Code	Proceedings of the 5th ACM Workshop on Security and Artificial Intelligence	978-1-4503-1664-4		10.1145/2381896.2381901	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2381896.2381901	"Malicious JavaScript code is widely used for exploiting vulnerabilities in web browsers and infecting users with malicious software. Static detection methods fail to protect from this threat, as they are unable to cope with the complexity and dynamics of interpreted code. In contrast, the dynamic analysis of JavaScript code at run-time has proven to be effective in identifying malicious behavior. During the execution of the code, however, damage may already take place and thus an early detection is critical for effective protection. In this paper, we introduce EarlyBird: a detection method optimized for early identification of malicious behavior in JavaScript code. The method uses machine learning techniques for jointly optimizing the accuracy and the time of detection. In an evaluation with hundreds of real attacks, EarlyBird precisely identifies malicious behavior while limiting the amount of malicious code that is executed by a factor of 2 (43%) on average."	2012	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:08	15–24							AISec '12				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library						alexa; custom_test_data; false_positive_rate; true_positive_rate	dynamic analysis; javascript attacks; machine learning																																														
3SZENRVS	conferencePaper	2003	"Sommer, Robin; Paxson, Vern"	Enhancing Byte-level Network Intrusion Detection Signatures with Context	Proceedings of the 10th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security	1-58113-738-9		10.1145/948109.948145	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/948109.948145	"Many network intrusion detection systems (NIDS) use byte sequences as signatures to detect malicious activity. While being highly efficient, they tend to suffer from a high false-positive rate. We develop the concept of contextual signatures as an improvement of string-based signature-matching. Rather than matching fixed strings in isolation, we augment the matching process with additional context. When designing an efficient signature engine for the NIDS bro, we provide low-level context by using regular expressions for matching, and high-level context by taking advantage of the semantic information made available by bro's protocol analysis and scripting language. Therewith, we greatly enhance the signature's expressiveness and hence the ability to reduce false positives. We present several examples such as matching requests with replies, using knowledge of the environment, defining dependencies between signatures to model step-wise attacks, and recognizing exploit scans.To leverage existing efforts, we convert the comprehensive signature set of the popular freeware NIDS snort into bro's language. While this does not provide us with improved signatures by itself, we reap an established base to build upon. Consequently, we evaluate our work by comparing to snort, discussing in the process several general problems of comparing different NIDSs."	2003	7/29/2014 16:44	7/29/2014 16:44	7/29/2014 16:44	262–271							CCS '03				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\THBXF6CD\Sommer and Paxson - 2003 - Enhancing Byte-level Network Intrusion Detection S.pdf		computational_time; custom_test_data; num_connections; slowdown	bro; evaluation; network intrusion detection; Pattern matching; security; signatures; snort																																														
9PIVBGS6	conferencePaper	2011	"Hofmann, Owen S.; Dunn, Alan M.; Kim, Sangman; Roy, Indrajit; Witchel, Emmett"	Ensuring Operating System Kernel Integrity with OSck	Proceedings of the Sixteenth International Conference on Architectural Support for Programming Languages and Operating Systems	978-1-4503-0266-1		10.1145/1950365.1950398	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1950365.1950398	"Kernel rootkits that modify operating system state to avoid detection are a dangerous threat to system security. This paper presents OSck, a system that discovers kernel rootkits by detecting malicious modifications to operating system data. OSck integrates and extends existing techniques for detecting rootkits, and verifies safety properties for large portions of the kernel heap with minimal overhead. We deduce type information for verification by analyzing unmodified kernel source code and in-memory kernel data structures. High-performance integrity checks that execute concurrently with a running operating system create data races, and we demonstrate a deterministic solution for ensuring kernel memory is in a consistent state. We introduce two new classes of kernel rootkits that are undetectable by current systems, motivating the need for the OSck API that allows kernel developers to conveniently specify arbitrary integrity properties."	2011	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:15	279–290							ASPLOS XVI				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library						computational_time; parsec; slowdown; spec2006	detection; rootkit																																														
6TZIIAVU	journalArticle	2009	"Hu, Yan; Chiu, Dah-Ming; Lui, John C. S."	Entropy Based Adaptive Flow Aggregation	IEEE/ACM Trans. Netw.		1063-6692	10.1109/TNET.2008.2002560	http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TNET.2008.2002560	"Internet traffic flow measurement is vitally important for network management, accounting and performance studies. Cisco's NetFlow is a widely deployed flow measurement solution that uses a configurable static sampling rate to control processor and memory usage on the router and the amount of reporting flow records generated. But during flooding attacks the memory and network bandwidth consumed by flow records can increase beyond what is available. Currently available countermeasures have their own problems: 1) reject new flows when the cache is full--some legitimate new flows will not be counted; 2) export not-terminated flows to make room for new ones--this will exhaust the export bandwidth; and 3) adapt the sampling rate to traffic rate--this will reduce the overall accuracy of accounting, including legitimate flows. In this paper, we propose an entropy based adaptive flow aggregation algorithm. Relying on information-theoretic techniques, the algorithm efficiently identifies the clusters of attack flows in real time and aggregates those large number of short attack flows into a few metaflows. Compared to currently available solutions, our solution not only alleviates the problem in memory and export bandwidth, but also significantly improves the accuracy of legitimate flows. Finally, we evaluate our system using both synthetic trace file and real trace files from the Internet."	Jun-09	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:14	698–711		3	17															ACM Digital Library						CSIM; memory_usage; processing_bandwidth; relative_error	data summarization; information theory; network monitoring; traffic measurement																																														
JKZVNF4H	conferencePaper	2000	"Lippmann, R.P.; Fried, D.J.; Graf, I; Haines, J.W.; Kendall, K.R.; McClung, D.; Weber, D.; Webster, S.E.; Wyschogrod, D.; Cunningham, R.K.; Zissman, M.A"	Evaluating intrusion detection systems: the 1998 DARPA off-line intrusion detection evaluation	"DARPA Information Survivability Conference and Exposition, 2000. DISCEX '00. Proceedings"			10.1109/DISCEX.2000.821506		"An intrusion detection evaluation test bed was developed which generated normal traffic similar to that on a government site containing 100's of users on 1000's of hosts. More than 300 instances of 38 different automated attacks were launched against victim UNIX hosts in seven weeks of training data and two weeks of test data. Six research groups participated in a blind evaluation and results were analyzed for probe, denial-of-service (DoS) remote-to-local (R2L), and user to root (U2R) attacks. The best systems detected old attacks included in the training data, at moderate detection rates ranging from 63% to 93% at a false alarm rate of 10 false alarms per day. Detection rates were much worse for new and novel R2L and DoS attacks included only in the test data. The best systems failed to detect roughly half these new attacks which included damaging access to root-level privileges by remote users. These results suggest that further research should focus on developing techniques to find new attacks instead of extending existing rule-based approaches"	2000	7/24/2014 18:54	7/24/2014 18:54		12-26 vol.2			2			Evaluating intrusion detection systems												IEEE Xplore				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\6QEM595N\abs_all.html; C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\KPJBV99X\Lippmann et al. - 2000 - Evaluating intrusion detection systems the 1998 D.pdf		DarpaIDE; false_positive_rate; roc; true_positive_rate	Arm; automated attacks; Automatic testing; Contracts; DARPA off-line intrusion detection evaluation; denial-of-service; Electrical capacitance tomography; Government; Internet; intrusion detection; intrusion detection systems; Laboratories; Read only memory; remote-to-local; rule-based approaches; safety systems; security of data; Training data; user to root																															"DARPA Information Survivability Conference and Exposition, 2000. DISCEX '00. Proceedings"															
84GMSDW5	conferencePaper	2013	"Narang, Pratik; Reddy, Jagan Mohan; Hota, Chittaranjan"	Feature Selection for Detection of Peer-to-peer Botnet Traffic	Proceedings of the 6th ACM India Computing Convention	978-1-4503-2545-5		10.1145/2522548.2523133	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2522548.2523133	"The use of anomaly-based classification of intrusions has increased significantly for Intrusion Detection Systems. Large number of training data samples and a good 'feature set' are two primary requirements to build effective classification models with machine learning algorithms. Since the amount of data available for malicious traffic will often be small compared to the available traces of benign traffic, extraction of 'good' features which enable detection of malicious traffic is a challenging area of work. This research work presents preliminary results of comparison of performance of three different feature selection algorithms - Correlation based feature selection, Consistency based subset evaluation and Principal component analysis-on three different Machine learning techniques- namely Decision trees, Naïve Bayes classifier, and Bayesian Network classifier. These algorithms are evaluated for the detection of Peer-to-Peer (P2P) based botnet traffic."	2013	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:01	16:1–16:9							Compute '13				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library						accuracy; computational_time; custom_test_data; recall	botnet; classification; feature selection; machine learning; peer-to-peer																																														
6APP2Z65	conferencePaper	2013	"Zaman, Safaa; El-Abed, Mohammed; Karray, Fakhri"	Features Selection Approaches for Intrusion Detection Systems Based on Evolution Algorithms	Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Ubiquitous Information Management and Communication	978-1-4503-1958-4		10.1145/2448556.2448566	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2448556.2448566	"Intrusion Detection Systems (IDSs) deal with large amount of data containing irrelevant and redundant features, which leads to slow training and testing processes, heavy computational resources and low detection accuracy. Therefore, the features selection is an important issue in intrusion detection. In this paper, we investigate the use of evolution algorithms for features selection approach in IDS. We compared the performance of three feature selection algorithms: Genetic Algorithms (GAs), Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO) and Differential Evolution (DE) using KDD Cup 1999 dataset. Our results show that DE is clearly and consistently superior compared to GAs and PSO for feature selection problems, both in respect to classification accuracy as well as number of features."	2013	7/29/2014 16:32	7/29/2014 16:32	7/29/2014 16:32	10:1–10:5							ICUIMC '13				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\8CVE8NZJ\Zaman et al. - 2013 - Features Selection Approaches for Intrusion Detect.pdf		accuracy; KDD99; num_data_iterations; num_features; num_generations; train_test_ratio	binary genetic algorithms; binary particle swarm optimization; differential evolution; evolution algorithms; features selection; intrusion detection systems																																														
RWH7G6KG	conferencePaper	2015	"Cai, Xiang; Lale, Rucha; Zhang, Xincheng; Johnson, Robert"	Fixing Races For Good: Portable and Reliable UNIX File-System Race Detection	"Proceedings of the 10th ACM Symposium on Information, Computer and Communications Security"	978-1-4503-3245-3		10.1145/2714576.2714581	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2714576.2714581	"We present a system for performing arbitrary sequences of filesystem operations and provably detecting any violation of serializable isolation semantics, i.e. any interleaving of attacker and defender actions is equivalent to a non-interleaved sequence of attacker and defender actions. Thus, our system provides a provably secure defense against all UNIX file-name race conditions, including the infamous access/open race. Our solution operates entirely in user-space and is portable to any POSIX.1-2008 system, making it usable today. Developers can adopt our solution selectively, using it for security-critical code and using the standard POSIX interface for non-security-critical parts of their programs. Furthermore, the proofs of correctness suggest several simple improvements to the POSIX standard."	2015	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:07	357–368						Fixing Races For Good	ASIA CCS '15				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library							file-system races; intrusion detection; operating-system security																																														
Z77JUKV2	conferencePaper	2008	"Chen, Shimin; Kozuch, Michael; Strigkos, Theodoros; Falsafi, Babak; Gibbons, Phillip B.; Mowry, Todd C.; Ramachandran, Vijaya; Ruwase, Olatunji; Ryan, Michael; Vlachos, Evangelos"	Flexible Hardware Acceleration for Instruction-Grain Program Monitoring	Proceedings of the 35th Annual International Symposium on Computer Architecture	978-0-7695-3174-8		10.1109/ISCA.2008.20	http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/ISCA.2008.20	"Instruction-grain program monitoring tools, which check and analyze executing programs at the granularity of individual instructions, are invaluable for quickly detecting bugs and security attacks and then limiting their damage (via containment and/or recovery). Unfortunately, their fine-grain nature implies very high monitoring overheads for software-only tools, which are typically based on dynamic binary instrumentation. Previous hardware proposals either focus on mechanisms that target specific bugs or address only the cost of binary instrumentation. In this paper, we propose a flexible hardware solution for accelerating a wide range of instruction-grain monitoring tools. By examining a number of diverse tools (for memory checking, security tracking, and data race detection), we identify three significant common sources of overheads and then propose three novel hardware techniques for addressing these overheads: Inheritance Tracking, Idempotent Filters, and Metadata-TLBs. Together, these constitute a general-purpose hardware acceleration framework. Experimental results show our framework reduces overheads by 2-3X over the previous state-of-the-art, while supporting the needed flexibility."	2008	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:09	377–388							ISCA '08				IEEE Computer Society	"Washington, DC, USA"						ACM Digital Library						precision; slowdown	Hardware Acceleration; Idempotent Filter; Inheritance Tracking; Instruction-grain Program Monitoring; LBA; Lifeguards; Log-Based Architectures; Metadata-TLB																																														
57BWEJ9T	conferencePaper	2012	"van Lunteren, Jan; Guanella, Alexis"	Hardware-accelerated regular expression matching at multiple tens of Gb/s		978-1-4673-0775-8 978-1-4673-0773-4 978-1-4673-0774-1		10.1109/INFCOM.2012.6195546	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6195546		Mar-12	8/11/2015 13:18	8/11/2015 20:02	8/11/2015 13:18	1737-1745											IEEE							CrossRef						scanning_time; scan_rate; true_positive_rate																																															
DSZNB33A	conferencePaper	2012	"Jyothsna, V.; Rama Prasad, V. V.; Munivara Prasad, K."	HFO-ANID: Hierarchical feature optimization for Anomaly Based Network Intrusion Detection				10.1109/ICCCNT.2012.6396095	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6396095		Jul-12	8/11/2015 13:05	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:05	11-Jan						HFO-ANID					IEEE							CrossRef						false_positive_rate; true_positive_rate																																															
UMZN447K	conferencePaper	2011	"Ishida, Moriteru; Takakura, Hiroki; Okabe, Yasuo"	High-Performance Intrusion Detection Using OptiGrid Clustering and Grid-Based Labelling		978-1-4577-0531-1		10.1109/SAINT.2011.12	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6004129		Jul-11	8/11/2015 13:12	8/12/2015 12:33	8/11/2015 13:12	19-Nov											IEEE							CrossRef						false_positive_rate; KDD99; Kyoto2006; recall; roc																																															
E49HPXV7	conferencePaper	2006	"Alicherry, Mansoor; Muthuprasanna, M.; Kumar, Vijay"	High Speed Pattern Matching for Network IDS/IPS		978-1-4244-0593-0 978-1-4244-0594-7		10.1109/ICNP.2006.320212	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4110291		Nov-06	8/11/2015 13:11	8/12/2015 2:11	8/11/2015 13:11	187-196											IEEE							CrossRef						scanning_time																																															
RT3NZ2Q2	journalArticle	2014	"Xu, Yang; Liu, Zhaobo; Zhang, Zhuoyuan; Chao, H. Jonathan"	High-Throughput and Memory-Efficient Multimatch Packet Classification Based on Distributed and Pipelined Hash Tables	IEEE/ACM Transactions on Networking		"1063-6692, 1558-2566"	10.1109/TNET.2013.2270441	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6565409		Jun-14	8/11/2015 12:57	8/12/2015 13:03	8/11/2015 12:57	982-995		3	22															CrossRef						clsf_speed; edge_detection; memory_usage																																															
EZQIFKET	journalArticle	2007	"Hwang, Kai; Cai, Min; Chen, Ying; Qin, Min"	Hybrid Intrusion Detection with Weighted Signature Generation over Anomalous Internet Episodes	IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing		1545-5971	10.1109/TDSC.2007.9	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4099191		Jan-07	8/11/2015 12:53	8/12/2015 13:25	8/11/2015 12:53	41-55		1	4															CrossRef						computational_time; MIT_LL; roc																																															
NWAPKXTA	conferencePaper	2012	"Aneetha, A. S.; Indhu, T. S.; Bose, S."	Hybrid Network Intrusion Detection System Using Expert Rule Based Approach	"Proceedings of the Second International Conference on Computational Science, Engineering and Information Technology"	978-1-4503-1310-0		10.1145/2393216.2393225	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2393216.2393225	"The usage of internet has almost become indispensable for information transaction and communication among people in various sections of the society. However as the network grows, secured information communication has become more vulnerable due to threats from unknown sources and hence the need for secured information sharing assumes greater importance in the present scenario. Various types of threats can be monitored by designing effective intrusion detection systems for providing security to the network. In this paper we have proposed a new frame work based on a hybrid intrusion detection system for known and unknown attacks in an efficient way. This frame work has the ability to detect intrusion in real time environment from the link layer. This has been achieved by combining rule base with appropriate clustering techniques for both supervised and unsupervised data. The known attack patterns are identified, with misuse detection system, using the rule base and, with anomaly detection, new attacks are identified by deploying clustering techniques. The new attacks have been updated in the rule base with the knowledge from an expert database that improved the efficiency of the system. The detection rate of the hybrid system has been found to increase as the unknown attack percentage increases whereas in misuse, detection rate is found to decrease and in anomaly detection rate remains constant."	2012	7/25/2014 19:39	7/25/2014 19:39	7/25/2014 19:39	47–51							CCSEIT '12				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\M4J2KS5H\Aneetha et al. - 2012 - Hybrid Network Intrusion Detection System Using Ex.pdf		KDD99; true_positive_rate	anomaly detection; clustering techniques; expert rule base; hybrid intrusion detection system; misuse detection																																														
NENG2V5H	conferencePaper	2012	"Anderson, Blake; Storlie, Curtis; Lane, Terran"	Improving Malware Classification: Bridging the Static/Dynamic Gap	Proceedings of the 5th ACM Workshop on Security and Artificial Intelligence	978-1-4503-1664-4		10.1145/2381896.2381900	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2381896.2381900	"Malware classification systems have typically used some machine learning algorithm in conjunction with either static or dynamic features collected from the binary. Recently, more advanced malware has introduced mechanisms to avoid detection in these views by using obfuscation techniques to avoid static detection and execution-stalling techniques to avoid dynamic detection. In this paper we construct a classification framework that is able to incorporate both static and dynamic views into a unified framework in the hopes that, while a malicious executable can disguise itself in some views, disguising itself in every view while maintaining malicious intent will prove to be substantially more difficult. Our method uses kernels to place a similarity metric on each distinct view and then employs multiple kernel learning to find a weighted combination of the data sources which yields the best classification accuracy in a support vector machine classifier. Our approach opens up new avenues of malware research which will allow the research community to elegantly look at multiple facets of malware simultaneously, and which can easily be extended to integrate any new data sources that may become popular in the future."	2012	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 14:37	8/11/2015 13:58	3–14						Improving Malware Classification	AISec '12				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library					http://dl.acm.org/ft_gateway.cfm?id=2381900&type=pdf	accuracy; auc; computational_time; false_positive_rate	computer security; machine learning; malware; multiple kernel learning																																														
I43K42M3	conferencePaper	2007	"Kruegel, Christopher; Balzarotti, Davide; Robertson, William; Vigna, Giovanni"	Improving Signature Testing through Dynamic Data Flow Analysis		978-0-7695-3060-4		10.1109/ACSAC.2007.40	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4412976		Dec-07	8/11/2015 13:05	8/12/2015 14:14	8/11/2015 13:05	53-63											IEEE							CrossRef						false_negative_rate																																															
W4648HKJ	conferencePaper	2010	"Papadogiannakis, Antonis; Polychronakis, Michalis; Markatos, Evangelos P."	Improving the Accuracy of Network Intrusion Detection Systems Under Load Using Selective Packet Discarding	Proceedings of the Third European Workshop on System Security	978-1-4503-0059-9		10.1145/1752046.1752049	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1752046.1752049	"Under conditions of heavy traffic load or sudden traffic bursts, the peak processing throughput of network intrusion detection systems (NIDS) may not be sufficient for inspecting all monitored traffic, and the packet capturing subsystem inevitably drops excess arriving packets before delivering them to the NIDS. This impedes the detection ability of the system and leads to missed attacks. In this work we present selective packet discarding, a best effort approach that enables the NIDS to anticipate overload conditions and minimize their impact on attack detection. Instead of letting the packet capturing subsystem randomly drop arriving packets, the NIDS proactively discards packets that are less likely to affect its detection accuracy, and focuses on the traffic at the early stages of each network flow. We present the design of selective packet discarding and its implementation in Snort NIDS. Our experiments show that selective packet discarding significantly improves the detection accuracy of Snort under increased traffic load, allowing it to detect attacks that would have otherwise been missed."	2010	7/25/2014 19:56	7/25/2014 19:56	7/25/2014 19:56	15–21							EUROSEC '10				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\NBVXIS8I\Papadogiannakis et al. - 2010 - Improving the Accuracy of Network Intrusion Detect.pdf		CPU_usage; packets_dropped; processing_bandwidth; throughput; true_positive_rate	intrusion detection; overload control; selective packet discarding																																														
VFJ5SAU4	conferencePaper	2008	"Amigoni, Francesco; Basilico, Fabrizio; Basilico, Nicola; Zanero, Stefano"	Integrating Partial Models of Network Normality via Cooperative Negotiation: An Approach to Development of Multiagent Intrusion Detection Systems	Proceedings of the 2008 IEEE/WIC/ACM International Conference on Web Intelligence and Intelligent Agent Technology - Volume 02	978-0-7695-3496-1		10.1109/WIIAT.2008.323	http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/WIIAT.2008.323	"Using agents for developing intrusion detection systems can provide several advantages, including configurability, adaptability, scalability, and robustness. Almost all works in agent-based intrusion detection have considered agents as elements that perform specific tasks in the intrusion detection process. In this paper, we propose a novel way of using agents to solve one of the most pressing problems in intrusion detection: the definition of an accurate model of network normality. We consider agents as associated to partial models of network normality that harmonize their conflicts via cooperative negotiation. Experimental results show that the proposed approach is promising."	2008	7/30/2014 0:55	7/30/2014 0:55	7/30/2014 0:55	531–537						Integrating Partial Models of Network Normality via Cooperative Negotiation	WI-IAT '08				IEEE Computer Society	"Washington, DC, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\DAGGPF6B\Amigoni et al. - 2008 - Integrating Partial Models of Network Normality vi.pdf		DarpaIDE; false_positive_rate; roc; true_positive_rate	cooperative negotiation; intrusion detection systems																																														
GBGJABGH	journalArticle	2007	"Hooper, Emmanuel"	Intelligent Detection and Response Strategies for Complex Attacks	IEEE Aerospace and Electronic Systems Magazine		0885-8985	10.1109/MAES.2007.4408519	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4408519		Nov-07	8/11/2015 13:09	8/12/2015 14:23	8/11/2015 13:09	12-Mar		11	22															CrossRef						conf_mtrx; custom_test_data; false_positive_rate																																															
7MNEPNIC	conferencePaper	2009	"Jormakka, Jorma; Lucenius, Jan"	Intruder Detection System Architecture for an SOA-Based C4I2SR System		978-1-4244-5166-1		10.1109/ComputationWorld.2009.73	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=5359600		Nov-09	8/11/2015 13:18	8/12/2015 14:53	8/11/2015 13:18	289-297											IEEE							CrossRef						custom_test_data; true_positve_rate																																															
HDWQ7IGC	conferencePaper	2012	"Ding, Qi; Katenka, Natallia; Barford, Paul; Kolaczyk, Eric; Crovella, Mark"	Intrusion As (Anti)Social Communication: Characterization and Detection	Proceedings of the 18th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining	978-1-4503-1462-6		10.1145/2339530.2339670	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2339530.2339670	"A reasonable definition of intrusion is: entering a community to which one does not belong. This suggests that in a network, intrusion attempts may be detected by looking for communication that does not respect community boundaries. In this paper, we examine the utility of this concept for identifying malicious network sources. In particular, our goal is to explore whether this concept allows a core-network operator using flow data to augment signature-based systems located at network edges. We show that simple measures of communities can be defined for flow data that allow a remarkably effective level of intrusion detection simply by looking for flows that do not respect those communities. We validate our approach using labeled intrusion attempt data collected at a large number of edge networks. Our results suggest that community-based methods can offer an important additional dimension for intrusion detection systems."	2012	7/29/2014 14:49	7/29/2014 14:49	7/29/2014 14:49	886–894						Intrusion As (Anti)Social Communication	KDD '12				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\V97UB56X\Ding et al. - 2012 - Intrusion As (Anti)Social Communication Character.pdf		custom_test_data; false_positive_rate; roc; true_positive_rate	intrusion detection; social graphs																																														
377S4GMN	journalArticle	2012	"Wei, Min; Kim, Keecheon"	Intrusion detection scheme using traffic prediction for wireless industrial networks	Journal of Communications and Networks		1229-2370	10.1109/JCN.2012.6253092	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6253092		Jun-12	8/11/2015 13:16	8/12/2015 15:39	8/11/2015 13:16	310-318		3	14															CrossRef						custom_test_data; false_positive_rate; true_positive_rate																																															
F62UQQV6	conferencePaper	2007	"Ramakrishnan, Vikram; Kumar, R. Anil; John, Sherin"	Intrusion Detection Using Protocol-based Non-Conformance to Trusted Behaviors		978-1-4244-1215-0 978-1-4244-1216-7		10.1109/ICNSURV.2007.384158	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4272190		Apr-07	8/11/2015 13:03	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:03	12-Jan											IEEE							CrossRef																																																					
NRDGWKVZ	journalArticle	2014	"Wang, Xiaofei; Liu, Bin; Jiang, Junchen; Xu, Yang; Wang, Yi; Wang, Xiaojun"	Kangaroo: Accelerating String Matching by Running Multiple Collaborative Finite State Machines	IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications		0733-8716	10.1109/JSAC.2014.2358841	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6905731		2014	8/11/2015 12:57	8/12/2015 17:55	8/11/2015 12:57	1-Jan						Kangaroo												CrossRef						DarpaIDE; memory_usage; num_distinct_transitions; scanning_time; scan_rate																																															
IMNXQDG6	journalArticle	2010	"Gupta, K.K.; Nath, B.; Kotagiri, R."	Layered Approach Using Conditional Random Fields for Intrusion Detection	IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing		1545-5971	10.1109/TDSC.2008.20	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=4479491		Jan-10	8/11/2015 12:56	8/12/2015 18:03	8/11/2015 12:56	35-49		1	7															CrossRef						accuracy; F-value; KDD99; recall																																															
TFIRQ3SN	conferencePaper	2010	"Vigna, Giovanni"	Network Intrusion Detection: Dead or Alive?	Proceedings of the 26th Annual Computer Security Applications Conference	978-1-4503-0133-6		10.1145/1920261.1920279	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1920261.1920279	"Research on network intrusion detection has produced a number of interesting results. In this paper, I look back to the NetSTAT system, which was presented at ACSAC in 1998. In addition to describing the original system, I discuss some historical context, with reference to well-known evaluation efforts and to the evolution of network intrusion detection into a broader field that includes malware detection and the analysis of malicious behavior."	2010	7/25/2014 19:48	7/25/2014 19:48	7/25/2014 19:48	117–126						Network Intrusion Detection	ACSAC '10				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\FRT5TDGM\Vigna - 2010 - Network Intrusion Detection Dead or Alive.pdf		MIT_LL; precision; recall	intrusion detection; network security																																														
TB9KP99X	conferencePaper	2012	"Sujatha, P. Kola; Priya, C. Suba; Kannan, A."	Network Intrusion Detection System Using Genetic Network Programming with Support Vector Machine	"Proceedings of the International Conference on Advances in Computing, Communications and Informatics"	978-1-4503-1196-0		10.1145/2345396.2345501	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2345396.2345501	"Nowadays Internet Services spread all over the world. There are large amount of data present in the internet services. However the internet services increases at the same time intrusions also increases. Network Intrusion Detection Systems are used to detect the intrusions in the network. For efficient Network Intrusion Detection System the preprocessing is most essential. In order to preprocess the dataset Support Vector Machine algorithm is used and that gives the new data model which has been used for creating rules for misuse detection. The dataset can be classified into two datasets; namely positive kernel and negative kernel. Positive Kernel is used for creating the rules. After classifying the dataset, fuzzification is applied to that datset and then the rules has been created by Genetic Network Programming which based on direct graph structure. In the testing phase the system has been used to detect the misuse activities. By combining SVM with Genetic Network Programming increases the performance of the detection rate of the Network Intrusion Detection Model and reduces the false positive rate."	2012	7/25/2014 19:55	7/25/2014 19:55	7/25/2014 19:55	645–649							ICACCI '12				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\UTFX2UM3\Sujatha et al. - 2012 - Network Intrusion Detection System Using Genetic N.pdf		false_positive_rate; KDD99; num_features; true_positive_rate	genetic network programming; KDDCUP'99 dataset; network intrusion detection system; RBF kernel function; support vector machine																																														
FHSQ76IQ	conferencePaper	2009	"Choudhary, Amit Kumar; Swarup, Akhilesh"	Neural Network Approach for Intrusion Detection	"Proceedings of the 2Nd International Conference on Interaction Sciences: Information Technology, Culture and Human"	978-1-60558-710-3		10.1145/1655925.1656163	http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/1655925.1656163	Intrusion Detection System is based on the belief that an intruder's behavior will be noticeably different from that of a legitimate user and would exploit security vulnerabilities. This paper proposes a neural network approach to improve the alert throughput of a network and making it attack prohibitive using IDS. For evolving and testing intrusion the KDD CUP 99 dataset are used. The result of proposed approach is found to be more efficient in the area of Intrusion Detection and promises a good scope for further research.	2009	7/28/2014 23:09	7/28/2014 23:09	7/28/2014 23:09	1297–1301							ICIS '09				ACM	"New York, NY, USA"						ACM Digital Library				C:\Users\Ryan\AppData\Roaming\Zotero\Zotero\Profiles\hn6tel97.default\zotero\storage\94H4X8G8\Choudhary and Swarup - 2009 - Neural Network Approach for Intrusion Detection.pdf		accuracy; KDD99	generalized regression neural network; intrusion detection system; Neural network																																														
AXH7HJQX	conferencePaper	2013	"Callegari, Christian; Casella, Alessandro; Giordano, Stefano; Pagano, Michele; Pepe, Teresa"	Sketch-based multidimensional IDS: A new approach for network anomaly detection		978-1-4799-0895-0		10.1109/CNS.2013.6682725	http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=6682725		Oct-13	8/11/2015 13:17	8/11/2015 13:55	8/11/2015 13:17	350-358						Sketch-based multidimensional IDS					IEEE							CrossRef						MAWILab; roc; slowdown																																															
